<worksheet xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main"><sheetPr><outlinePr summaryBelow="1" summaryRight="1" /><pageSetUpPr /></sheetPr><dimension ref="A1:F138" /><sheetViews><sheetView workbookViewId="0"><selection activeCell="A1" sqref="A1" /></sheetView></sheetViews><sheetFormatPr baseColWidth="8" defaultRowHeight="15" /><sheetData><row r="1"><c r="A1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>title</t></is></c><c r="B1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>abstract</t></is></c><c r="C1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>keywords</t></is></c><c r="D1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>language</t></is></c><c r="E1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>page_start</t></is></c><c r="F1" t="inlineStr"><is><t>page_end</t></is></c></row><row r="2"><c r="A2" t="inlineStr"><is><t>روشی جدید برای یافتن آماره های ناوردای ما کسیمال با ابزار عمل گروه و استفاده از توابع هم وردا</t></is></c><c r="B2" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله روش جدیدی برای ساختن آماره ناوردای ما کسیمال ارائه می شود و به کمک چند تابع هم وردا، آماره ناوردای ما کسیمال به دست می آید. در پایان نشان داده می شود در حالتی که عمل گروه، یک ز یر گروه نرمال به طور یکتا انتقالی دارد نیز می توان آماره ناوردای ما کسیمال را محاسبه کرد.</t></is></c><c r="C2" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گروه توپولوژیکی، آماره ناوردای ما کسیمال، براوردگر هم وردا، تابع تک وردا، ز یرگروه نرمال. 62F10, 54H11</t></is></c><c r="D2" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E2" t="n"><v>13</v></c><c r="F2" t="n"><v>20</v></c></row><row r="3"><c r="A3" t="inlineStr"><is><t>برخی خواص ا کستروپی گذشته تعمیم یافته موزون و مقایسه برخی ترتیب های تصادفی</t></is></c><c r="B3" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله تعمیم جدیدی از ا کستروپی گذشته تجمعی موزون، که ا کستروپی گذشته تعمیم یافته موزون نامیده می شود را معرفی و خواص آن را مطالعه می کنیم. همچنین پس از بیان ترتیب تصادفی مر بوط به این اندازه، برخی ویژگی های آن را مورد بررسی قرار داده و نیز روابط میان چند ترتیب تصادفی را مطالعه می کنیم.</t></is></c><c r="C3" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فزونی ثروت مرتبه دوم، ا کستروپی گذشته تجمعی موزون، آنتروپی تسالیس باقیمانده تجمعی موزون، ترتیب های تغییر پذیری . 94A17, 62N05</t></is></c><c r="D3" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E3" t="n"><v>21</v></c><c r="F3" t="n"><v>29</v></c></row><row r="4"><c r="A4" t="inlineStr"><is><t>معرفی یک پایه در روش گالرکین بر اساس پایه موجک چندگانه لژاندر</t></is></c><c r="B4" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله به معرفی یک پایه در روش گالرکین می پردازیم. برای این منظور با استفاده از پایه موجک چندگانه لژاندر یک پایه متشکل از توابع به اندازه کافی هموار و صادق در شرط دیر یکله ارایه می دهیم. همچنین یک کران باال برای خطای جواب ضعیف حاصل از روش گالرکین به دست می آور یم.</t></is></c><c r="C4" t="inlineStr"><is><t>موجک های چندگانه لژاندر، روش گالرکین، کران باالی خطا. 65L20, 65N30, 42C40</t></is></c><c r="D4" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E4" t="n"><v>30</v></c><c r="F4" t="n"><v>34</v></c></row><row r="5"><c r="A5" t="inlineStr"><is><t>روش حلی برای مسائل برنامه ریزی خطی کسری بازه ای</t></is></c><c r="B5" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در بسیاری از مسائل بهینه سازی نسبت اهداف از بهینه سازی هر هدف به تنهایی، دید و بینش بهتری ارائه می دهد یا شرایط مسئله به گونه ا ی است که باید نسبت اهداف بهینه شود. یکی از ابزارهای کارا و متداول در مواجه با این مسائل، به کارگیری رویکرد برنامه ر یزی خطی کسری است. اما از آنجا که در ا کثر مسائل موجود در دنیای واقعی، اطالعات غیرقطعی و مبهم هستند، در این مقاله نیز مسائل برنامه ر یزی خطی کسری با ضرایب بازه ای در تابع هدف مدنظر قرار می گیرند. به منظور برخورد با چنین مسائلی از یک ترتیب در اعداد بازه ای استفاده می شود.نتایج در یک مثال عددی مورد بررسی قرار می گیرند.</t></is></c><c r="C5" t="inlineStr"><is><t>برنامه ر یزی خطی کسری، برنامه ر یزی بازه ای. 90C05, 90C32</t></is></c><c r="D5" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E5" t="n"><v>35</v></c><c r="F5" t="n"><v>39</v></c></row><row r="6"><c r="A6" t="inlineStr"><is><t>حل عددی معادله تلگراف کسری با استفاده از ماتریس عملیاتی چبیشف</t></is></c><c r="B6" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله یک روش محاسباتی مبتنی بر روش طیفی تاو و چندجمله ای های چبیشف انتقال یافته برای حل معادالت تلگراف کسری زمان ارائه می شود. برای حل این دسته از معادالت از ماتر یس عملیاتی مشتقات کسری چندجمله ای های چبیشف استفاده نموده و این دسته از معادالت را به دستگاهی از معادالت جبری تبدیل نموده و سپس جواب را به دست خواهیم آورد. مشتق کسری مورد استفاده در این مقاله از نوع مشتق کسری کاپوتو است. همچنین پیاده سازی این روش ساده بوده و نتایج دقیقی را به همراه دارد</t></is></c><c r="C6" t="inlineStr"><is><t>چندجمله ای های چبیشف، روش طیفی تاو، ماتر یس عملیاتی، مشتق کسری کاپوتو، معادله تلگراف کسری. 65L03, 65L10, 65N35</t></is></c><c r="D6" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E6" t="n"><v>40</v></c><c r="F6" t="n"><v>46</v></c></row><row r="7"><c r="A7" t="inlineStr"><is><t>حل عددی معادله بگلی‐تورویک با استفاده از موجک لژاندر</t></is></c><c r="B7" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله یک روش محاسباتی برای حل معادله دیفرانسیل کسری بگلی ‐تورویک ارائه می شود که روش مبتنی بر موجک های لژاندر است. در این تحقیق با استفاده از ماتر یس عملیاتی مشتق کسری به دست آمده از ماتر یس تبدیل چندجمله ای های موجک لژاندر برای حل معادالت دیفرانسیل کسری استفاده نموده و این دسته از معادالت را به دستگاهی از معادالت جبری تبدیل می نمائیم. در ادامه دو مثال عددی برای نشان دادن قابلیت روش مطرح می شود.</t></is></c><c r="C7" t="inlineStr"><is><t>چندجمله ای های لژاندر انتقال یافته، موجک لژاندر، ماتر یس عملیاتی، مشتق کسری. 65T60￿ 42C40￿ 34K37</t></is></c><c r="D7" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E7" t="n"><v>47</v></c><c r="F7" t="n"><v>54</v></c></row><row r="8"><c r="A8" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یک روش ناحیه اعتماد تطبیقی کارا</t></is></c><c r="B8" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله یک روش ناحیه اعتماد تطبیقی را برای حل مسائل بهینه سازی نامقید پیشنهاد می دهیم. در این روش، از ترکیب حالت یکنوا و نایکنوا، یک نسبت ناحیه اعتماد اصالح شده را به کار می بر یم. این نسبت، بیانگر اطالعات مفیدی از رابطه بین مدل پیشنهادی و مسئله اصلی است. همچنین، به منظور جلوگیری از حل مجدد ز یر مسئله زمانی که طول گام رد می شود، جستجوی خطی آرمیژو استفاده می گردد. تحت شرایط استاندارد، همگرایی سراسری و همگرایی ز برخطی الگوریتم پیشنهادی قابل اثبات است. نتایج عددی حاصل از پیاده سازی الگوریتم بر روی برخی مسائل آزمون حا کی از کارایی و برتری روش پیشنهادی نسبت به سایر الگوریتم های مورد مقایسه در ادبیات موضوع است.</t></is></c><c r="C8" t="inlineStr"><is><t>بهینه سازی نامقید، جستجوی خطی غیردقیق، روش ناحیه اعتماد، همگرایی سراسری. 65K05, 90C30, 90C06</t></is></c><c r="D8" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E8" t="n"><v>55</v></c><c r="F8" t="n"><v>60</v></c></row><row r="9"><c r="A9" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یک روش چهارگامی با همگرایی مرتبه ۶۳ برای حل معادالت غیرخطی</t></is></c><c r="B9" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله یک روش تکراری چهارگامی برای حل معادالت غیرخطی معرفی می کنیم. الگوریتم جدید مبتنی بر روش های تکراری نیوتن، هالی، استیفنسن و هوس هولدر می باشد که دارای مرتبه همگرایی ۶۳ است. نتایج عددی نشان می دهد که روش جدید در مقایسه با روش های تکراری دیگر با تعداد تکرارهای کمتری معادالت غیرخطی را حل می کند.</t></is></c><c r="C9" t="inlineStr"><is><t>روش چهارگامی، معادالت غیرخطی، روش های تکراری، آنالیز همگرایی. 11D04, 34A34</t></is></c><c r="D9" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E9" t="n"><v>61</v></c><c r="F9" t="n"><v>64</v></c></row><row r="10"><c r="A10" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یک روش بارزیالی‐بوروین اصالح شده برای حل معادالت قدرمطلقی</t></is></c><c r="B10" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله با اصالح روش بارز یالی‐بوروین یک روش جدید برای حل معادالت قدرمطلقی معرفی می کنیم. همچنین تحت برخی فرض های استاندارد همگرایی روش جدید را بررسی می کنیم. با ارائه یک مثال SOR عددی کارایی الگوریتم جدید برای حل معادالت قدرمطلقی را با برخی روش های دیگر از جمله شبه ، نیوتن تعمیم یافته و عالمت اصالح شده مقایسه می کنیم. نتایج عددی برتری و کارایی روش بارز یالی‐بوروین اصالح شده را نشان می دهد.</t></is></c><c r="C10" t="inlineStr"><is><t>روش بارز یالی‐بوروین، معادالت قدرمطلقی، آنالیز همگرایی، نتایج عددی. 49N05, 11D04</t></is></c><c r="D10" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E10" t="n"><v>65</v></c><c r="F10" t="n"><v>69</v></c></row><row r="11"><c r="A11" t="inlineStr"><is><t>حل معادالت تابعی به کمک نمایش گروه های متناهی</t></is></c><c r="B11" t="inlineStr"><is><t>معادالت تابعی معادالتی هستد که مجهول آن ها به جای متغیرهای معمولی، تابع هستند. با این حال، روش های مورد استفاده برای حل معادالت تابعی ممکن است کامال متفاوت با روش های حل معادالت متغیری باشد. معادالت تابعی اطالعاتی در باره یک تابع یا چند تابع ارائه می کنند. دراین مقاله قصد داریم به کمک ساختار گروه های متناهی، بعضی از معادالت تابعی را حل می کنیم.</t></is></c><c r="C11" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گروه، نمایش های گروه، معادالت تابعی. 20C35, 11F66</t></is></c><c r="D11" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E11" t="n"><v>79</v></c><c r="F11" t="n"><v>83</v></c></row><row r="12"><c r="A12" t="inlineStr"><is><t>نتایجی روی همریختی ها و مدول های تقریباً یکدست</t></is></c><c r="B12" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله مدول های تقر یباً یکدست را مورد بررسی قرار می دهیم. فرض می کنیم یک حلقه ̸ mT = T R T d موضعی نوتری از بعد ، یک جبر جابجایی ا کید با عنصر یکه ۱ روی باشدکه . دنباله های تقر یباً T − − T T دقیق از مدول ها را تعر یف کرده و مدول های تقر یباً یکدست را تعر یف می کنیم. همچنین، همر یختی های − w W T R تقر یباً یکدست صادق را بین جبرهای و تعر یف می کنیم که در اینجا دارای ویژگی های مشابه به − R T به عنوان جبر است و نتایجی در رابطه با مدول های تقر یباً یکدست و همر یختی های تقر یباً یکدست ارائه می دهیم.</t></is></c><c r="C12" t="inlineStr"><is><t>حلقه های تقر یبی، مدول های تقر یباً یکدست، همر یختی های تقر یباً یکدست . 18A32, 18F20, 39B42</t></is></c><c r="D12" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E12" t="n"><v>84</v></c><c r="F12" t="n"><v>88</v></c></row><row r="13"><c r="A13" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(cid:0)</t></is></c><c r="B13" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله فرض می کنیم ۵ عدد اول دلخواهی است و p خم بیضوی متناظر با آن می باشد. در این مقاله ما نشان می دهیم حد اقل رتبه خانواده دو است. برای این منظور، دو نقطه خاص را پیدا و ثابت می کنیم هر دو تا نقطه مستقل هستند. در ادامه نشان می دهیم که دو نقطه مورد نظر می توانند قسمتی از پایه برای این خانواده باشند.</t></is></c><c r="C13" t="inlineStr"><is><t>خم بیضوی ، ارتفاع کانونی ،نقاط تابی ،نقاط مستقل و مولد. 11G05, 11D59, 11G50</t></is></c><c r="D13" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E13" t="n"><v>89</v></c><c r="F13" t="n"><v>96</v></c></row><row r="14"><c r="A14" t="inlineStr"><is><t>طیف الپالسی و الپالسی بدون عالمت گراف مانستر</t></is></c><c r="B14" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ا گر دو گراف استارالیک و مولتی فن را در دو راس با بیشتر ین درجه ادغام کنیم، گراف حاصل را یک گراف مانستر مینامیم. در این سخنرانی ما برآنیم که به بررسی طیفهای الپالسی و الپالسی بدون عالمت گراف مانستر بپردازیم .</t></is></c><c r="C14" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گراف مانستر ،طیف الپالسی ، طیف الپالسی بدون عالمت. 05C50</t></is></c><c r="D14" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E14" t="n"><v>97</v></c><c r="F14" t="n"><v>101</v></c></row><row r="15"><c r="A15" t="inlineStr"><is><t>بررسی درک دانشجویان از مفهوم درخت با استفاده از تجزیه ژنتیکی نظریه SOPA</t></is></c><c r="B15" t="inlineStr"><is><t>مفهوم درخت از مفاهیم اساسی در نظر یه گراف است. با این حال پژوهش های کمی در زمینه بررسی درک دانشجویان از این مفهوم ر یاضی وجود دارد. در این پژوهش به بررسی چگونگی ساخت مفهوم درخت در ذهن دانشجویان پرداخته شده است. بدین منظور یک تجز یه ژنتیکی اولیه از مفهوم درخت در ابتدا ارائه می شود. سپس این مدل فرضی، با کمک داده های جمع آوری شده از ۸۱ نفر از دانشجویان کارشناسی یکی از دانشگاه های شرق کشور که در مصاحبه نیمه ساختار یافته شرکت کرده اند مورد بازبینی قرار می گیرد. نتایج این مطالعه ساختارهای ذهنی خاصی را نشان می دهد که نقش کلیدی در توسعه درک دانشجویان از مفهوم درخت ایفا می کنند. عالوه بر آن در این پژوهش مشکالت رایج دانشجویان در این مفهوم ر یاضی شناسایی و گزارش گردیده است.</t></is></c><c r="C15" t="inlineStr"><is><t>درخت، نظر یه گراف، درک ر یاضی، نظر یه ،SOPA تجز یه ژنتیکی. 97K30, 97C70, 97C30</t></is></c><c r="D15" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E15" t="n"><v>102</v></c><c r="F15" t="n"><v>107</v></c></row><row r="16"><c r="A16" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یافتن کوتاه ترین مسیر برای ربات های دارای محدودیت در چرخش</t></is></c><c r="B16" t="inlineStr"><is><t>مسأله یافتن کوتاه تر ین مسیر یکی از مسائل کالسیک در زمینه گراف و هندسه محاسباتی است. در این مقاله مسأله کوتاه تر ین مسیر بر روی مجموعه ای از نقاط در صفحه بررسی شده است به شکلی که پیمایش در بین نقاط آزادانه نبوده و دارای محدودیت در چرخش است. در اینجا الگوریتمی از مرتبه زمانی چند جمله ای برای حل این مسأله ارائه شده است. این الگوریتم برای مسیر یابی در ر بات هایی که دارای محدودیت در چرخش هستند کارامد است.</t></is></c><c r="C16" t="inlineStr"><is><t>کوتاه تر ین مسیر، محدودیت در چرخش، طراحی مسیر. 68U05, 05C85, 05C38</t></is></c><c r="D16" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E16" t="n"><v>108</v></c><c r="F16" t="n"><v>116</v></c></row><row r="17"><c r="A17" t="inlineStr"><is><t>محاسبه شاخص وینر یک نانوتوروس و شبیه سازی در پایتون</t></is></c><c r="B17" t="inlineStr"><is><t>شاخص وینر یک نامتغیر گرافیکی است که کاربرد گسترده ای در شیمی دارد. این شاخص به صورت ∑ W(G) = / d(x, y) ۲ ۱ { }⊆ x,y V (G) ∈ d(x,y) x, y V (G) G V(G) تعر یف می شود که در آن مجموعة تمام راس های است و در رابطه با عبارت ، y x نشانگر طول حداقل مسیر بین و است. در این مقاله که بر اساس مقاالت شادروان پرفسور علیرضا اشرفی T = T [m, n] نوشته شده، الگوریتمی برای محاسبة ماتر یس فاصلة نانوتورس ارائه می شود. با استفاده از نرم افزار پایتون الگوریتم شبیه سازی می شود و شاخص وینر برای ماتر یس های مختف بدست می آید.</t></is></c><c r="C17" t="inlineStr"><is><t>شاخص وینر، نانوتورس. 05C12</t></is></c><c r="D17" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E17" t="n"><v>117</v></c><c r="F17" t="n"><v>121</v></c></row><row r="18"><c r="A18" t="inlineStr"><is><t>از چه مرتبه هایی حدا کثر پنج گروه پوچ توان وجود دارد؟</t></is></c><c r="B18" t="inlineStr"><is><t>تعداد گروه های پوچ توان از مرتبه را با نشان می دهیم. در این مقاله یک مشخصه سازی از Nil &lt; k &lt; α (n) = k n اعداد طبیعی ارائه خواهیم داد که به ازای آنها که ۶ ۱. Nil</t></is></c><c r="C18" t="inlineStr"><is><t>عدد پوچتوان، عدد آبلی، گروه با مرتبه خالی از مر بع، گروه با مرتبه خالی از مکعب. 20D99</t></is></c><c r="D18" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E18" t="n"><v>127</v></c><c r="F18" t="n"><v>129</v></c></row><row r="19"><c r="A19" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گرافهای خنثی‐ عالمت دار و بررسی ویژگیهای آن</t></is></c><c r="B19" t="inlineStr"><is><t>هرگاه گراف ساده ای دارای یال های عالمت دار و بدون عالمت باشد، انگاه این دسته از گراف ها را گرافهای خنثی‐ عالمت دار گویند.در این مقاله به بررسی برخی از ویژگیهای این دسته از گرافها همانند چند جمله ای گراف،رابطه ضرایب چند جمله ای با برخی از ویژگیهای گراف مانند تعداد یالها وتعداد مثلث ها .... ، بررسی طیف برخی از این نوع گراف ها مانند دور، ستاره و مسیر و انرژی گراف های نامبرده میپردازیم .</t></is></c><c r="C19" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گراف خنثی‐عالمت دار،چندجمله ای گراف های خنثی‐عالمت دار،طیف گراف های خنثی‐ عالمت دار ،انرژی گراف های خنثی‐ عالمت دار. ۱. مقدمه</t></is></c><c r="D19" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E19" t="n"><v>130</v></c><c r="F19" t="n"><v>134</v></c></row><row r="20"><c r="A20" t="inlineStr"><is><t>کاربردهایی از قدم زدن تصادفی روی گراف ها</t></is></c><c r="B20" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله ابتدا قدم زدن تصادفی روی گراف ها را تشر یح و برخی از مهمتر ین پارامترهایی که در این مسئله مورد توجه قرار می گیرند را معرفی می نماییم. سپس برخی از قضایا در مورد این پارامترهای اصلی را ارائه می کنیم و نهایتا برخی از کاربردهای مهم آنها را مورد بررسی قرار می دهیم.</t></is></c><c r="C20" t="inlineStr"><is><t>قدم زدن تصادفی روی گراف ها، زمان دسترسی، زمان پوشش، نرخ اختالط . 05C50, 15A18, 60J10</t></is></c><c r="D20" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E20" t="n"><v>135</v></c><c r="F20" t="n"><v>139</v></c></row><row r="21"><c r="A21" t="inlineStr"><is><t>بعد متریک ‐خوشه غیرمحلی کسری گراف ها</t></is></c><c r="B21" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فرض کنید یک گراف همبند باشد. تابع ۱ ۰ را تابع مولد − خوشه غیرمحلی { } ⩾ f (R u, v ) G Y X G برای گوییم، هرگاه برای هر دو خوشه غیرمجاور و از داشته باشیم ۱ که در آن { } { ∈ | ̸ } k R u, v = x V (G) d(u, x) = d(v, x) . در این مقاله، بعد متر یک ‐خوشه غیرمحلی − {| | | } k cdim (G) = min g g G کسری گراف را به صورت یک تابع مولد غیرمحلی است − nonl f تعر یف می کنیم. همچنین، این پارامتر را برای برخی از ضرب های گراف ها بررسی می کنیم. k k</t></is></c><c r="C21" t="inlineStr"><is><t>تابع مولد − خوشه غیرمحلی کسری، بعد متر یک ‐خوشه غیرمحلی کسری. 05C15, 05C69</t></is></c><c r="D21" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E21" t="n"><v>140</v></c><c r="F21" t="n"><v>143</v></c></row><row r="22"><c r="A22" t="inlineStr"><is><t>نتایجی در مورد عدد رنگی تفکیک پذیر یالی برخی گراف ها</t></is></c><c r="B22" t="inlineStr"><is><t>هدف از این مقاله معرفی رنگ آمیزی تفکیک پذیر یالی یک گراف و بیان نتایجی برای این نوع رنگ آمیزی می باشد. در این مقاله به ارائه مقادیر دقیق یا کران باالی عدد رنگی تفکیک پذیر یالی گراف های دور، دوبخشی کامل، پترسن و نیز حاصل ضرب کرونای دو گراف می پردازیم.</t></is></c><c r="C22" t="inlineStr"><is><t>عدد رنگی تفکیک پذیر یالی، گراف پترسن، حاصل ضرب کرونا، گراف دوبخشی کامل، گراف دور. 05C12, 05C15</t></is></c><c r="D22" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E22" t="n"><v>144</v></c><c r="F22" t="n"><v>147</v></c></row><row r="23"><c r="A23" t="inlineStr"><is><t>مقادیر ویژه الپالسی بی عالمت در گراف</t></is></c><c r="B23" t="inlineStr"><is><t>انرژی گراف، به مجموع قدر مطلق مقادیر ویژه آن و انرژی الپالسی گراف، به مجموع قدر مطلق تفاوت m ۲ بین مقادیر ویژه الپالسی و بیان می گردد. در این نوشته، طیف الپالسی بی عالمت برخی از گراف های خاص n را محاسبه و سپس کران هایی را برای انرژی الپالسی بی عالمت گراف ها تخمین خواهیم نمود.</t></is></c><c r="C23" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گراف، طیف الپالسی بی عالمت، انرژی الپالسی بی عالمت . 05C50</t></is></c><c r="D23" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E23" t="n"><v>148</v></c><c r="F23" t="n"><v>151</v></c></row><row r="24"><c r="A24" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یافتن عدد وینر برای گراف پلی تیوفتن و ارائه یک چند جمله ای درجه سه با استفاده از عدد</t></is></c><c r="B24" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فرض کنید گراف مر بوط به مولکول پلی تیوفن باشد،به طوری که مجموعه رئوس با و مجموعه یال ها با E نشان داده می شوند. مجموعه تمام فاصله های بین هر دو راس از گراف G را پایای وینر گویند و با )G(W نشان می دهند. دراین مقاله روشی برای بدست آوردن پایای گراف وینر و همچنین چند جمله P T ای درجه سه برای گراف پلی تیوفن با استفاده از مقدار n که نمایانگر تعداد پنج ضلعی های موجود در گراف مورد نظر است ارائه شده است.</t></is></c><c r="C24" t="inlineStr"><is><t>پلی تیوفن، پایای وینر، گراف . ۱. مقدمه</t></is></c><c r="D24" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E24" t="n"><v>152</v></c><c r="F24" t="n"><v>155</v></c></row><row r="25"><c r="A25" t="inlineStr"><is><t>بررسی فاصله در گراف های توانی نوع اول</t></is></c><c r="B25" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فرض می کنیم گرافی ساده و بدون جهت باشد. گراف های توانی متعددی برای گراف V G تعر یف شده است. مجموعه رئوس این گرافهای توانی، مجموعه توانی میباشد و مجموعهی یالهای آنها با توجه به نوع گراف توانی تعر یف میشود. در این مقاله قصد داریم فاصله بین رئوس در گراف توانی نوع اول را بررسی کرده و نتایج مرتبط با فاصلهی رئوس ارائه دهیم.</t></is></c><c r="C25" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گراف توانی، فاصله در گراف. 05C12 ,05C76</t></is></c><c r="D25" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E25" t="n"><v>156</v></c><c r="F25" t="n"><v>161</v></c></row><row r="26"><c r="A26" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یک روش ناحیه اعتماد تطبیقی نایکنوای تصادفی</t></is></c><c r="B26" t="inlineStr"><is><t>امروزه روش های تقر یبی تصادفی به عنوان دسته ای از روش های کارا برای حل مسائل مقیاس بزرگ مورد توجه قرار گرفته اند. در این راستا، در این مقاله یک روش ناحیه اعتماد تصادفی را ارائه می دهیم. روش پیشنهادی برای حل ز یرمساله ناحیه اعتماد از تکنیک گرادیان مزدوج استفاده می کند. از سوی دیگر با استفاده از فرآیند ز یرنمونه گیری به محاسبه مقادیر بردار گرادیان و ماتر یس هسیان می پردازد. همچنین، همگرایی سراسری الگوریتم پیشنهادی تحت برخی شرایط استاندارد اثبات می شود. نتایج عددی حاصل از پیاده سازی الگوریتم بر روی مجموعه داده ها بیانگر کارایی الگوریتم جدید برای حل مسائل مقیاس بزرگ است.</t></is></c><c r="C26" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ناحیه اعتماد، بهینه سازی نامقید، شعاع تطبیقی، بهینه سازی تصادفی. 65K05, 65K10, 90C60</t></is></c><c r="D26" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E26" t="n"><v>162</v></c><c r="F26" t="n"><v>167</v></c></row><row r="27"><c r="A27" t="inlineStr"><is><t>تشخیص دقیق خودروهای مورب</t></is></c><c r="B27" t="inlineStr"><is><t>با گسترش روز افزون داده های تصویری، درک محتوای تصویرها توسط سیستم های خودکار، اهمیت ویژه ای پیدا کرده است. در این زمینه، شناسایی خودرو در تصویرها به دلیل پیش نیاز بودن در بسیاری از کاربردها، مورد توجه پژوهشگران می باشد. از جمله این کاربردها عبارتند از: تشخیص خودرو، نوع خودرو، رنگ، اندازه خودرو. روش های موجود یک ضعف اساسی دارند که عکس خودروها از رو برو یا به پهلو بود. با به وجود آمدن شبکه های عصبی کانولوشنالی و قابلیت مناسب آن ها به منظور تشخیص ویژگی های اشیاء، از این شبکه ها برای شناسایی اشیاء در تصویرها بهره برده شد که به ایجاد روش های گونا گونی منجر شد. یکی از این روش ها که نسبت به هم رده های خود از دقت و کارایی باالیی برخوردار است، شبکه aniteR می باشد. به دلیل کارآمدی این مدل، از این روش برای شناسایی خودروهای مورب استفاده شده است. مدل با استفاده از مجموعه داده های جمع آوری شده از سطح شهر و دوربین های شهرداری آموزش داده شده است و این مدلِ آموزش دیده با قدرت شناسایی باالیی، قادر به شناسایی خودرو در زاویه های مختلف و شرایط نوری متفاوت می باشد.</t></is></c><c r="C27" t="inlineStr"><is><t>شناسایی خودرو مورب، شبکه های عصبی کانولوشنالی، تشخیص شی ۸ پارامتری، . Retina هکبش ۱. مقدمه تشخیص شی مورب یکی از مسائل مهم در پردازش تصویر است که در طول سالیان ز یادی مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در ابتدا، برای تشخیص اشیاء مورب، از الگوریتم های سنتی مانند تبدیل هاف و تبدیل فوریه استفاده می شد. این الگوریتم ها با تشخیص تغییرات در فضای فرکانس، تالش می کردند تا شی های مورب و چرخان را شناسایی کنند. اما این روش ها دارای محدودیت هایی مانند حساسیت به نویز و تشخیص ناصحیح در صورت وجود خطا در تشخیص یا تغییرات کوچک در شی بودند. پژوهشگران این حوزه با استخراج ویژگی های تصویر و الگوریتم یادگیری آدابوست به روش مناسبی مانند ویوال‐جونز دست یافتند و با استفاده از توصیفگر هیستگرام گرادیان جهت دار تصویر و ماشین بردار پشتیبان، موفق به شناسایی خودرو در تصاویر شدند.]۱، ۲[ با پیشرفت تکنولوژی، شبکه های عصبی کانولوشنی )NNC( به عنوان یک روش موثر در تشخیص شی های مورب و چرخان معرفی شدند]۳[. این شبکه ها با استفاده از درون یابی تصویر و استخراج ویژگی های مهم، قادر به تشخیص دقیق و سر یع تر شی های مورب شدند. در سال های اخیر، با پیشرفت روش های یادگیری عمیق و شبکه هایی مانند شبکه</t></is></c><c r="D27" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E27" t="n"><v>168</v></c><c r="F27" t="n"><v>173</v></c></row><row r="28"><c r="A28" t="inlineStr"><is><t>بررسی مروری کاربرد هوش مصنوعی در آموزش ریاضیات</t></is></c><c r="B28" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فناوری پیشرفتۀ هوش مصنوعی فرصتی برای حل و بهبود عملکردهای آموزشی و یادگیری جهت کمک به معلمان و دانش آموزان فراهم می کند. هوش مصنوعی به تجر به و داده ها نیاز دارد تا هوش آن بتواند به خوبی اجرا شود. مزایای متعددی در استفاده از هوش مصنوعی در یادگیری و آموزش ر یاضیات وجود دارد؛ از جمله اینکه دانش آموزان در مواجهه با راه حل های روزانه و درک بهتر مسائل اساسی هندسه، ر یاضیات و آمار انتقاد پذیرتر و مسئولیت پذیرتر می شوند. هدف این پژوهش، ارائه یک نمای کلی از هوش مصنوعی در آموزش و یادگیری ر یاضیات برای دانش آموزان در تمام سطوح آموزشی می¬باشد. در این مقاله، یافته های تجز یه و تحلیل ۰۲ نشر یه پژوهشی منتشر شده بین سال های ۷۱۰۲ تا ۱۲۰۲ ارائه شده که به بررسی این موضوع می پردازد که چگونه هوش مصنوعی ممکن است بر عملکرد دانش آموزان ر یاضی تأثیر بگذارد و آن ها را افزایش دهد. در بین رویکردهای مختلف آموزش ر یاضی، ر باتیک بیشتر ین استفاده را برای دانش آموزان ر یاضی، معلمان و آموزشی داشته است. با کمک هوش مصنوعی، آموزش و یادگیری مؤثرتر خواهد شد؛ز یرا هیجان انگیز و خالقانه بودن، درک آن را برای دانش آموزان آسان تر کرده است.</t></is></c><c r="C28" t="inlineStr"><is><t>هوش مصنوعی، آموزش ر یاضی، سیستم اطالعاتی، ر باتیک، آموزش نظام مند. 05C12, 05C15</t></is></c><c r="D28" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E28" t="n"><v>174</v></c><c r="F28" t="n"><v>180</v></c></row><row r="29"><c r="A29" t="inlineStr"><is><t>یک روش گرادیان مزدوج اصالح شده برای حل مسائل بهینه سازی ناهموار در بازسازی تصویر</t></is></c><c r="B29" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در این مقاله، یک الگوریتم گرادیان مزدوج اصالح شده برای حل مسائل مینیمم سازی تابع پیوسته لیپ شیتز موضعی در مقیاس بزرگ، پیشنهاد می شود. الگوریتم گرادیان مزدوج کالسیک برای تعیین جهت جستجو در حالت هموار، از اطالعات تابع گرادیان و جهت کاهشی قبلی استفاده می کند. در حالی که اطالعات مرتبه اول مشتق برای توابع ناهموار وجود ندارد، از این رو ابتدا با بکارگیری تابع منظم ساز مورآ – یاشیدا تابع ناهموار به تابعی هموار تبدیل می شود. سپس با معرفی برخی شرایط استاندارد برای تابع ناهموار، الگوریتم گرادیان مزدوج اصالح شده پیشنهاد می گردد. نشان داده می شود که جهت تولید شده توسط الگوریتم در هر تکرار جهتی کاهشی است و الگوریتم دارای خاصیت همگرایی سراسری می باشد. نتایج عددی برای توابع هموار و ناهموار در مقیاس بزرگ نشان می دهد که الگوریتم پیشنهادی در مقایسه با سایر روش های بهینه سازی مشابه برتری دارد. همچنین کارایی الگوریتم پیشنهادی در حل مسئله بازسازی تصویر نشان داده می شود.</t></is></c><c r="C29" t="inlineStr"><is><t>روش گرادیان مزدوج، تابع نامحدب و ناهموار، همگرایی سراسری، پیوسته لیپ شیتز موضعی . 90C26</t></is></c><c r="D29" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E29" t="n"><v>181</v></c><c r="F29" t="n"><v>182</v></c></row><row r="30"><c r="A30" t="inlineStr"><is><t>استفاده از موجک های در حل عددی معادالت انتگرال فردهلم فازی غیرخطی نوع دوم</t></is></c><c r="B30" t="inlineStr"><is><t>در سالیان اخیر، انواع مختلفی از توابع پایه ای در حل عددی انواع معادالت انتگرال به کار رفته اند، که از آن جمله می توان به چندجمله ای های تیلور، توابع متعامد و موجک ها اشاره کرد. هر کدام از این توابع پایه ای، مزایا و معایب خاص خود را دارند، اما آنچه که از مقاالت منتشر شده در این سال ها قابل استخراج است، می توان گفت که بیشتر محققین عالقه مند به استفاده از پایه های چندجمله ای در معادالت مختلف هستند. پایه های چندجمله ای عالوه بر سادگی بیشتر نسبت به سایر پایه ها، دقت قابل قبولی در حل عددی انواع معادالت انتگرال دارند. CAS اما یکی از پایه هایی که کمتر مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است، موجک های هستند. واقعیت غیرقابل CAS انکار آن است که موجک های در بسیاری از معادالت )و البته نه همه آنها( دارای کارایی و درجه دقت باالیی نیستند و بنابراین استفاده از پایه های چندجمله ای، هم از نظر هز ینه محاسباتی و هم از نظر دقت عاقالنه تر CAS است. اما ارزش موجک های به عنوان توابع پایه ای زمانی مشخص می شود که توابع به کار رفته در معادالت، CAS متناوب و علی الخصوص مثلثاتی باشند. در چنین معادالتی، موجک های با هز ینه محاسباتی پایین، تقر یبی با دقت بسیار باال ارائه می کنند، و حتی در بسیاری از موارد به جواب دقیق منجر می شوند. CAS نویسندگان در ]۱[، موجک های را در حل عددی معادالت فردهلم فازی خطی نوع دوم به کار گرفته اند. در این مقاله، از این موجک ها در حل عددی معادالت فردهلم فازی غیرخطی نوع دوم استفاده می کنیم و نتایج حاصل را در قالب چند مثال عددی ارائه می نماییم. مثال های عددی به گونه ای انتخاب شده اند که توابع به کار رفته در آنها مثلثاتی هستند. لذا نتایج با دقت بسیار باال در این مثال ها حاصل شده است. CAS</t></is></c><c r="C30" t="inlineStr"><is><t>معادالت فردهلم فازی غیرخطی نوع دوم، موجک های ، روش گالرکین. 65T60, 34A07, 45B05</t></is></c><c r="D30" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E30" t="n"><v>183</v></c><c r="F30" t="n"><v>184</v></c></row><row r="31"><c r="A31" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گرافهای توانی و ساخت اشکال موبیوسی</t></is></c><c r="B31" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فرض می کنیم گرافی ساده و بدون جهت باشد. در این مقاله به معرفی چند نوع گراف C توانی میپردازیم، میتوان مالحظه کرد که با استفاده از گراف توانی ایجاد شده توسط دور ، یک نوار موبیوس ۴ C ساخته میشود. همچنین با استفاده از یک گراف دو دوری شامل و مفهوم گراف توانی به ساختاری شامل دو ۴ نوار موبیوس به هم چسبیده خواهیم رسید که آن را پروانهی موبیوس مینامیم. در ادامه با استفاده از نوع دیگری از C یک گراف سه دوری شامل ساختار دیگری شامل سه نوار موبیوس حاصل میشود که آن را تندیس موبیوس ۴ نامگذاری کرده ایم. برای اطالعات بیشتر در مورد گرافهای توانی مراجع ]۱، ۲، ۳، ۴[ را مالحظه فرمایید.</t></is></c><c r="C31" t="inlineStr"><is><t>گراف توانی، نوار موبیوس. 05C12 ,05C76</t></is></c><c r="D31" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E31" t="n"><v>185</v></c><c r="F31" t="n"><v>186</v></c></row><row r="32"><c r="A32" t="inlineStr"><is><t>اثر حاصل ضرب توانهای ماتریسهای مجاورت در ماتریس درجه</t></is></c><c r="B32" t="inlineStr"><is><t>فرض کنید گراف ساده از مرتبه با باشد. ا گر دنباله درجات این ۲ ۱ deg(G) = (d , d , . . . , d ) گراف به صورت باشد، ماتر یس قطری درجات و ماتر یس مجاورت گراف را n ۲ ۱ A ∆ به ترتیب با و نشان می دهند. به مجموع عناصر روی قطر اصلی یک ماتر یس دلخواه اثر آن گفته می شود، در این پژوهش به بررسی اثر ضرب ماتر یس مجاروت در ماتر یس قطری درجات در برخی توان ها می پردازیم.</t></is></c><c r="C32" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ماتر یس مجاورت ، ماتر یس قطری درجات ، اثر ماتر یس. 05C50</t></is></c><c r="D32" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fa</t></is></c><c r="E32" t="n"><v>187</v></c><c r="F32" t="n"><v>187</v></c></row><row r="33"><c r="A33" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Strong dominating sets of graphs: A Survey</t></is></c><c r="B33" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G = (V, E) be a simple graph. A set D ⊆ V is a strong dominating set of G, if for every vertex x ∈ V \ D there is a vertex y ∈ D with xy ∈ E(G) and deg(x) ≤ deg(y). The strong domination number γ (G) st is defined as the minimum cardinality of a strong dominating set. The strong domatic number of G is the maximum number of strong dominating sets into which the vertex set of can be partitioned. In this paper, we summarize new results on this subject. More precisely, we study the strong domination number of some operations on a graph, the strong domination number of Haj ́os sum and vertex-sum of two graphs and strong domatic number of a graph.</t></is></c><c r="C33" t="inlineStr"><is><t>strong dominating set, Hajo ́s sum, vertex-sum</t></is></c><c r="D33" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E33" t="n"><v>17</v></c><c r="F33" t="n"><v>22</v></c></row><row r="34"><c r="A34" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Universal Localizations and Auslander-Reiten Conjecture</t></is></c><c r="B34" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this short note, we provide a link between one of the most rigorous homological conjectures, namely Auslander-Reiten Conjecture, and a particular type of ring epimorphisms. More specifically, we show how the validity of Auslander-Reiten conjecture for a finite dimensional algebra A is connected to the phenomenon that ring epimorphisms starting from A are universal localizations.</t></is></c><c r="C34" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Finite dimensional algebra, Ring epimorphism</t></is></c><c r="D34" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E34" t="n"><v>23</v></c><c r="F34" t="n"><v>26</v></c></row><row r="35"><c r="A35" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Extension of Logic Algebras To Superhyper Logic</t></is></c><c r="B35" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper considers the logic algebra structures and generalizaied them to superhyper logic algebras. Indeed, we extended the axioms of logic algebra to neutrosophic superhyper logic algebras.</t></is></c><c r="C35" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Logic algebra, neutrosophic logic, superhyper logic</t></is></c><c r="D35" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E35" t="n"><v>27</v></c><c r="F35" t="n"><v>30</v></c></row><row r="36"><c r="A36" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Enhancing Gro ̈bner System Computation through</t></is></c><c r="B36" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper improves the efficiency of computing Gr ̈obner systems GVWDisPGB over the existing algorithm [4], so-called GES-GVW-CGS al- gorithm. The GES-GVW-CGS algorithm employs parametric linear algebra techniques for the initial partitioning of the parameter space and constructs fewer branches, leading to reduced complexity. Experimental evaluation on a diverse set of benchmark polynomials using Maple implementation demon- GVWDisPGB strates that the proposed algorithm is faster than the algo- rithm. GVWDisPGB</t></is></c><c r="C36" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Gro ̈bner systems, GES algorithm</t></is></c><c r="D36" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E36" t="n"><v>31</v></c><c r="F36" t="n"><v>36</v></c></row><row r="37"><c r="A37" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Where Algebra comes to help Business Markets;</t></is></c><c r="B37" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Algebra is as crucial in business as in other fields. A business owner makes use of algebraic operations to calculate the profits or losses incurred. A business person will employ algebra to decide whether a piece of equipment does not lose it’s worthwhile it is in stock. Also, the business owner needs to calculate the lowest price at which an item can be sold to still cover the expenses. As for the people working in the finance area, exchange rates and interest rates are often represented algebraically; therefore, good knowledge of algebraic operations is necessary to carry out finances accurately. .</t></is></c><c r="C37" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Algebra, Break-Even Point (BEP), business</t></is></c><c r="D37" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E37" t="n"><v>37</v></c><c r="F37" t="n"><v>40</v></c></row><row r="38"><c r="A38" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Shape Graph On Hyper Algebraic Structure</t></is></c><c r="B38" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper considers the hyperalgebra structures and introduced the derived graph and hypergraph via the subahperalgebra structures such as multigroups, hyperideal, and normal heart.</t></is></c><c r="C38" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Shape Graph, general hyperring, heart</t></is></c><c r="D38" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E38" t="n"><v>41</v></c><c r="F38" t="n"><v>44</v></c></row><row r="39"><c r="A39" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Almost Hilbert C -Module Derivations</t></is></c><c r="B39" t="inlineStr"><is><t>∗ Let M be a Hilbert C -module. In this paper, we showe that ∗ for any approximate Hilbert C -module derivation f : M → M under some ∗ special control functions, there exists a unique Hilbert C -module derivation φ : M → M, near the function f . We prove the Isac-Rassias stability of ∗ Hilbert C -module derivations. ∗</t></is></c><c r="C39" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Hilbert C -module, derivation, approximate functional</t></is></c><c r="D39" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E39" t="n"><v>45</v></c><c r="F39" t="n"><v>50</v></c></row><row r="40"><c r="A40" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Modules in which every its finitely generated submodule</t></is></c><c r="B40" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We study an R-module M whenever for every proper finitely generated submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. Such modules are R called co-finite-retractable (simply CFR). We consider when factors module, direct sum and direct summand of CFR modules is CFR. Also, we investigate the injective hull of CFR modules.</t></is></c><c r="C40" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Co-finite-retractable, Co-retractable</t></is></c><c r="D40" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E40" t="n"><v>51</v></c><c r="F40" t="n"><v>53</v></c></row><row r="41"><c r="A41" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A note on unit-clean rings</t></is></c><c r="B41" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We define and explore a new class of rings called unit-clean rings that strictly contain the class of clean rings. An element a in R is defined to be unit-clean if there exists invertible elements u, v in R and an idempotent e in R such that au = e + v. A ring R is unit-clean if and only each of its elements are unit-clean. we show that for an idempotent e in a ring R if eRe and (1 − e)R(1 − e) are unit-clean rings, then R is a unit-clean ring. This implies that the matrix ring M (R) over a unit-clean ring is n unit-clean. Also extensions of unit-clean rings are studied, including group rings.</t></is></c><c r="C41" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ring, unit-clean</t></is></c><c r="D41" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E41" t="n"><v>54</v></c><c r="F41" t="n"><v>57</v></c></row><row r="42"><c r="A42" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Medium nil- -clean rings</t></is></c><c r="B42" t="inlineStr"><is><t>∗ A ∗-ring R is called a medium nil- -clean ring if every element in R sum or difference of a nilpotent element and a projection that ∗ commute. In this paper we obtain some properties of medium nil- -clean rings and we also check the relationship of these rings with other studied ∗ ∗ -clean and strongly weakly J- -clean rings. ∗ ∗</t></is></c><c r="C42" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Projection, Medium nil- -clean ring, Strongly -clean</t></is></c><c r="D42" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E42" t="n"><v>58</v></c><c r="F42" t="n"><v>61</v></c></row><row r="43"><c r="A43" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the NSE Characterization of the Alternative Simple</t></is></c><c r="B43" t="inlineStr"><is><t>For a group G, π (G) and s (G) are denoted the set of orders e m of elements and the number of elements of order m in G, respectively. Let nse(G) = {s (G) | m ∈ π (G)}. An arbitrary finite group M is NSE m e characterization if, for every group G, the equality nse(G) = nse(M) implies ∼ that G = M. In this paper, we are going to show that the non-Abelian finite simple group A , is characterizable by NSE. 9</t></is></c><c r="C43" t="inlineStr"><is><t>element order, finite simple group, prime graph</t></is></c><c r="D43" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E43" t="n"><v>62</v></c><c r="F43" t="n"><v>65</v></c></row><row r="44"><c r="A44" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A Fixed Point Approach to Almost Orthogonally Quadratic</t></is></c><c r="B44" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let A be an orthogonality non-Archimedean C*-algebra with ∗ the orthogonality defined on it by x ⊥ y if x y = 0. In this paper, we prove the generalized Hyers-Ulam stability and super-stability of orthogonally quadratic ∗-homomorphisms on A and we prove some corollaries about it. ∗</t></is></c><c r="C44" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Orthogonality, non-Archimedean C -algebra</t></is></c><c r="D44" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E44" t="n"><v>66</v></c><c r="F44" t="n"><v>71</v></c></row><row r="45"><c r="A45" t="inlineStr"><is><t>States on Hyper Equality Algebras</t></is></c><c r="B45" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we consider bounded hyper equality algebras and introduce the notions of Bosbach, inf-bosbach, and sup-Bosbach on these algebras and discuss the related properties. We investigate the relations among Bosbach, inf-bosbach, sup-Bosbach on bounded hyper equality algebras. Moreover, we construct some quotient hyper equality algebras by sup-Bosbach (inf-Bosbach) states.</t></is></c><c r="C45" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Bosbach state, bounded hyper equality algebra, equality</t></is></c><c r="D45" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E45" t="n"><v>72</v></c><c r="F45" t="n"><v>77</v></c></row><row r="46"><c r="A46" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A note on parainjective and paraprojective S-acts</t></is></c><c r="B46" t="inlineStr"><is><t>New kinds of acts, namely parainjective and paraprojective acts over a monoid are introduced and investigated. Some general properties of these acts and their relations with projective (injective) S-acts are studied. It is shown that for injective (projective) acts the concepts projectivity (injectivity) and paraprojectivity (parainjectivity) are equivalent.</t></is></c><c r="C46" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Parainjective, paraprojective, monoid, S-act</t></is></c><c r="D46" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E46" t="n"><v>78</v></c><c r="F46" t="n"><v>81</v></c></row><row r="47"><c r="A47" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Heart-Based Hyperideal of General superring</t></is></c><c r="B47" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper considers the concept of general superrings as an extension of superrings and investigates and analyzes some of their essential properties. This study defines the notation of hyperideals in general superrings considers the notation of homomorphism and prove the (general) theorems isomorphism in general superrings, viathe heart of general superhyperring.</t></is></c><c r="C47" t="inlineStr"><is><t>General superring, Boolean general superring, (normal)hyperideal, heart of general superring</t></is></c><c r="D47" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E47" t="n"><v>82</v></c><c r="F47" t="n"><v>86</v></c></row><row r="48"><c r="A48" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Γ-δ-MV -algebras</t></is></c><c r="B48" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we introduce Γ-δ-MV -algebras and study some properties of them. Also, we define the notion of an ideal of an Γ-δ-MV - algebra and define the notion of the ideal of generated by subset of an Γ-δ- MV -algebra. Finally, we show that (Id(A), ∧, ∨, {0}, A) is a Heyting algebra, where Id(A) is the set of ideals of Γ-δ-MV -algebra A.</t></is></c><c r="C48" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Γ-δ-MV -algebra, ideals, Heyting algebra</t></is></c><c r="D48" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E48" t="n"><v>87</v></c><c r="F48" t="n"><v>91</v></c></row><row r="49"><c r="A49" t="inlineStr"><is><t>dual Rickart modules and isomorphisms</t></is></c><c r="B49" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this note, we shall introduce a new aspect of d-Rickart modules namely virtually d-Rickart modules via the concept of isomorphisms. We provide a condition to ensure us a ds of such modules inherits the property. Some examples are also presented.</t></is></c><c r="C49" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ds, isomorphism, d-Rickart module, virtually d-Rickart</t></is></c><c r="D49" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E49" t="n"><v>92</v></c><c r="F49" t="n"><v>96</v></c></row><row r="50"><c r="A50" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Co-retractable and CFR modules</t></is></c><c r="B50" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We study an R-module M whenever for every proper submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. Such modules are called R coretractable. Amini and et al. investigate coretractable module, and we also obtain some new results of coretractable module. We show that, every module over a left Artinian left H-ring is coretractable. Also, we show that every module M has finite length over a commutative ring R is R coretractable. It is clear, every coretractable module is CFR. We consider conditions which under that conditions CFR module and coretractable module are equivalent. We show that, every CFR module is coretractable if and only if every module is coretractable.</t></is></c><c r="C50" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Co-finite-retractable, Co-retractable</t></is></c><c r="D50" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E50" t="n"><v>97</v></c><c r="F50" t="n"><v>99</v></c></row><row r="51"><c r="A51" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Computation of Krasner hyperrins and Mp-hyperrings of</t></is></c><c r="B51" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This article presents a computation of various types of hyperrings, including Krasner hyperrins and MP-hyperrings, in small orders and provides a classification of these hyperrings based on their Cayley tables..</t></is></c><c r="C51" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Krasner, Enumeration, Hyperring</t></is></c><c r="D51" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E51" t="n"><v>100</v></c><c r="F51" t="n"><v>104</v></c></row><row r="52"><c r="A52" t="inlineStr"><is><t>HOCHSCHILD COHOMOLOGY OF SQUARE MATRIX</t></is></c><c r="B52" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let S = be an algebra, where A and B are algebras N B over an arbitrary commutative ring R , M is a left A-module and right B-module and N is a left B-module and right A-module. We establish the existence of two long exact sequence of R-modules that relate the Hochschild cohomology of A, B, M and N. Sabsequently, we delve into the investigation the Hochschild cohomology of S. Finally, we compute the Hochschild cohomology of square algebra.</t></is></c><c r="C52" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Hochschild cohomology, Square matrix algebra, Square</t></is></c><c r="D52" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E52" t="n"><v>105</v></c><c r="F52" t="n"><v>109</v></c></row><row r="53"><c r="A53" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Gauss-Jordan Systems</t></is></c><c r="B53" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we study the Gauss-Jordan form of parametric matrices. Using the concept of linearly dependency systems for linear systems involving parameters [2], we introduce the notion of a Gauss-Jordan system for a parametric matrix, i.e. we decompose the space of parameters into a finite set of cells and for each cell, we give the corresponding Gauss-Jordan elimination of the matrix. We also present an algorithm for computing a Gauss-Jordan system for a given parametric matrix.</t></is></c><c r="C53" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Parametric linear algebra, Gauss-Jordan system</t></is></c><c r="D53" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E53" t="n"><v>110</v></c><c r="F53" t="n"><v>115</v></c></row><row r="54"><c r="A54" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Z −ideals in MV-algebras</t></is></c><c r="B54" t="inlineStr"><is><t>◦ In this article, the notions of Z −ideals is introduced and several equivalent definitions is given. We try to identify the elements of these ideals and their relationship with minimal prime ideals. Also, we will ◦ investigate Z −ideals of MV−chain. ◦</t></is></c><c r="C54" t="inlineStr"><is><t>MV-algebras, Minimal prime ideal, Z −ideals</t></is></c><c r="D54" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E54" t="n"><v>116</v></c><c r="F54" t="n"><v>120</v></c></row><row r="55"><c r="A55" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(n + 4)-dimensional nilpotent n-Lie algebras with</t></is></c><c r="B55" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we classify (n + 4)-dimensional nilpotent n-Lie algebras of class 3 and 4 with 4-dimensional derived subalgebra over an arbitrary field, when n ≥ 3.</t></is></c><c r="C55" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Filippov algebra, nilpotent n-Lie algebra</t></is></c><c r="D55" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E55" t="n"><v>121</v></c><c r="F55" t="n"><v>126</v></c></row><row r="56"><c r="A56" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Computing Gro ̈bner Bases via the Cousin Complex:</t></is></c><c r="B56" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Gr ̈obner bases are a fundamental tool in commutative algebra and algebraic geometry, with a wide range of applications in areas such as coding theory, robotics, and cryptography. In this paper, we present a new method for computing Gr ̈obner bases using the Cousin complex, a power- ful tool from algebraic geometry. We provide algorithms for constructing the Cousin complex, computing its cohomology, and using the resulting co- homology to obtain a Gr ̈obner bases in a chosen monomial ordering. We also demonstrate the effectiveness of this method on a variety of examples, including polynomial ideals arising in coding theory, robotics, and cryptog- raphy. Our results show that the Cousin complex provides a powerful new approach to computing Gro ̈bner bases, with potential applications in a wide range of fields.</t></is></c><c r="C56" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Gro ̈bner bases, Cousin complex, Monomial order</t></is></c><c r="D56" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E56" t="n"><v>127</v></c><c r="F56" t="n"><v>132</v></c></row><row r="57"><c r="A57" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Sum-hypergraph on modules</t></is></c><c r="B57" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let P be an R-module. We define a hypergraph on P where the vertices are all nontrivial submodules of P and a set W (such that i | W |≥ 2) of nontrivial submodules of P forms a hyperedge provided the i sum of each two distinct elements of W is equal to P and W is maximal i i with respect to this property. We denote such hypergraph via SUM (P ). R Some general properties of such hypergraphs are considered.</t></is></c><c r="C57" t="inlineStr"><is><t>small submodule, semisimple module, hyperedge</t></is></c><c r="D57" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E57" t="n"><v>133</v></c><c r="F57" t="n"><v>137</v></c></row><row r="58"><c r="A58" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A note on UJI rings</t></is></c><c r="B58" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, UJI rings are studied. A ring R is called UJI if U(R) = J (R) + Inv(R) ∩ Z(R). We obtain some properties of UJI rings.</t></is></c><c r="C58" t="inlineStr"><is><t>UJI ring, 2-UJ ring, involution</t></is></c><c r="D58" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E58" t="n"><v>138</v></c><c r="F58" t="n"><v>140</v></c></row><row r="59"><c r="A59" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Study of classical prime submodules</t></is></c><c r="B59" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The aim of this paper is to introduce the concept of classical prime submodules which is the generalization of the notion of weakly prime submodules to modules over arbitrary noncommutative rings. We study some properties of classical prime submodules and investigate their structure in different classes of modules. In particular, this yields characterizations of classical prime submodules in multiplication modules and also modules over duo rings.</t></is></c><c r="C59" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Prime submodule, Classical prime submodule, Weakly</t></is></c><c r="D59" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E59" t="n"><v>141</v></c><c r="F59" t="n"><v>145</v></c></row><row r="60"><c r="A60" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The interrelation between variouse notions of L-Uniform</t></is></c><c r="B60" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The study of uniformity structures on L-valued spaces has been extensively explored in the literature.uniformity, in particular, has emerged as a useful tool for investigating topology, proximity, closure, and interior operators. In this article, we present a new definition of fuzzy uniform spaces by introducing the concept of gradation of uniformity in the non-empty set X. Specifically, we present the notions of L-uniform spaces, and L-Hutton uniform spaces. We investigate the relationship between Sostak L-fuzzy topological spaces and these aforementioned uniformities. Furthermore, we demonstrate the relation between Hutton L-uniformities andHutton uniformities and L-uniformities in the case of (L, ≤, ∧, 0). ̃</t></is></c><c r="C60" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Sostak L-fuzzy topological spaces,L-uniform spaces, L-</t></is></c><c r="D60" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E60" t="n"><v>146</v></c><c r="F60" t="n"><v>150</v></c></row><row r="61"><c r="A61" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A study on weakly reversible rings</t></is></c><c r="B61" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this research, one see an extension of reversible rings named weakly reversible ring. Also, one peruse the connection between weakly reversible rings and semicommutative rings. In the continuation of this research, it is asserted that a ring R is weakly reversible ring iff R[x] is weakly reversible ring. Finally, one peruse conditions that the power series ring and skew polynomial rings are weakly reversible.</t></is></c><c r="C61" t="inlineStr"><is><t>weakly reversible ring, polynomial ring</t></is></c><c r="D61" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E61" t="n"><v>151</v></c><c r="F61" t="n"><v>155</v></c></row><row r="62"><c r="A62" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On α-nilpotent pair of polygroups</t></is></c><c r="B62" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we define the notion of α-nilpotent pair of polygroups and we show some of their properties. Also, we get a relation between α-nilpotent pair of polygroups and α-nilpotent pair of groups.</t></is></c><c r="C62" t="inlineStr"><is><t>polygroup, pair of group, nilpotent pair of polygroup</t></is></c><c r="D62" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E62" t="n"><v>156</v></c><c r="F62" t="n"><v>160</v></c></row><row r="63"><c r="A63" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Lie Symmetries and Optimal System of a Third-Order</t></is></c><c r="B63" t="inlineStr"><is><t>n this paper a less studied nonlinear partial defferential equation of the third-order is under consideration. Important properties concerning advanced character such like lie symmetries, lie group slutions and optimal system the equation of continuity are given. Characteristic wave properties such like dispersion relations and both the group and phase velocitioes are derived explicitly. In addition, we discuss the non-classical case relating to potential symmetries for the first time. Further partical applications in several domains of sciences we discuss in detail approximate symmetries. Finally, as a further new contribution we deduce new generalized symmetries of lower order. Some important notes ralating to future inntensions are given.</t></is></c><c r="C63" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Nonlinear partial differential equations, evolution</t></is></c><c r="D63" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E63" t="n"><v>161</v></c><c r="F63" t="n"><v>166</v></c></row><row r="64"><c r="A64" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Colocal-global Principle for the artinianness of generalized</t></is></c><c r="B64" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we study colocalization of generalized local homol- ogy modules. We extend some results of [5] to generalized local homology modules. In fact, the dual of Faltings’ Local-global Principle for generalized local homology modules will be investigated.</t></is></c><c r="C64" t="inlineStr"><is><t>colocalization, generalized local homology modules</t></is></c><c r="D64" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E64" t="n"><v>167</v></c><c r="F64" t="n"><v>171</v></c></row><row r="65"><c r="A65" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Noether Symmetries and corresponding conservation laws</t></is></c><c r="B65" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Since Emmy Noether proved that there is a one-to-one correspondence between symmetry groups and conservation laws. A new range of symmetries called Neother symmetries were formed. In this article, we are trying to obtain the Noether symmetries of the mKdV equation and show by finding the conservation law by direct method that corresponding to each of the mentioned symmetries, a similar survival law is obtained.</t></is></c><c r="C65" t="inlineStr"><is><t>mKdV equation, Neother symmetries, direct method</t></is></c><c r="D65" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E65" t="n"><v>172</v></c><c r="F65" t="n"><v>176</v></c></row><row r="66"><c r="A66" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Some properties of fuzzy algebraic structures of QIF SN(G)</t></is></c><c r="B66" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In previous works, by using norms, we investigated some properties of fuzzy algebraic structures, specially, we defined and investigated Q-fuzzy subgroups, anti Q-fuzzy subgroups, Level subsets and translations Q-fuzzy subgroups, level subsets and translations of anti Q-fuzzy Subgroups and Q-intuitionistic fuzzy subgroups with respect to norms. In this paper, we introduce the concepts conjugate, direct product, normality, order, normalized, characteristic, composition and general characterristic between Q-intuitionistic fuzzy subgroups under norms(T and C) and obtain some results about them.</t></is></c><c r="C66" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Q-intuitionistic fuzzy subgroups, norms, conjugate</t></is></c><c r="D66" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E66" t="n"><v>177</v></c><c r="F66" t="n"><v>182</v></c></row><row r="67"><c r="A67" t="inlineStr"><is><t>on unit-semi boolean rings</t></is></c><c r="B67" t="inlineStr"><is><t>It was defined in [3] the class of semi-boolean rings as those rings R in which every element is the sum of an element from the Jacobson radical and an idempotent. we extend this class of rings as rings for each element, there exists at least one unit, such that their product is the sum of an idempotent and an element of the Jacobson radical. We call these rings unit semi-boolean. We discuss, in the present paper, some properties of unit semi-boolean rings. Moreover, we prove that every ring R is unit semi-boolean if and only if the quotient ring R/P (R) is unit semi-boolean. Finally, we prove that the transpose of any invertible matrix over unit-semi boolean rings is invertible.</t></is></c><c r="C67" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ring, unit-semi boolean</t></is></c><c r="D67" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E67" t="n"><v>183</v></c><c r="F67" t="n"><v>187</v></c></row><row r="68"><c r="A68" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Engel soft polygroups</t></is></c><c r="B68" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we introduce Engel soft polygroups. Also, we study the intersection, extended intersection, restricted union of two Engel soft polygroups.</t></is></c><c r="C68" t="inlineStr"><is><t>polygroup, soft set, Engel polygroup</t></is></c><c r="D68" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E68" t="n"><v>188</v></c><c r="F68" t="n"><v>193</v></c></row><row r="69"><c r="A69" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Capability of low dimensional nilpotent 3-Lie algebras</t></is></c><c r="B69" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we determine the capability of n-Lie algebras of dimension at most n + 3 over an arbitrary field and the capability of 7-dimensional nilpotent 3-Lie algebras over field K with charK ≠ 2 by calculating of Schur multiplier when n &gt; 2.</t></is></c><c r="C69" t="inlineStr"><is><t>capable n-Lie algebra, nilpotent n-Lie algebra</t></is></c><c r="D69" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E69" t="n"><v>194</v></c><c r="F69" t="n"><v>199</v></c></row><row r="70"><c r="A70" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Generalizations of prime ideals</t></is></c><c r="B70" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this article we inveastigate some properties of weakly prime ideals in arbitrary unital rings and we generalize the notion of weakly semiprime ideal to arbitrary unital rings. The relationship among the families of weakly prime ideals, prime ideals, semiprime ideals and weakly semiprime ideals of a ring R is considered. Also, the structure of such ideals on duo rings is described.</t></is></c><c r="C70" t="inlineStr"><is><t>weakly prime ideal, weakly semiprime ideal, duo ring</t></is></c><c r="D70" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E70" t="n"><v>200</v></c><c r="F70" t="n"><v>204</v></c></row><row r="71"><c r="A71" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the closed submodules</t></is></c><c r="B71" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let R be a commutative ring with identity, and M be an R- module. Let K be a proper submodule of M. Recall that K is (α, β)-closed α β submodule if r m ∈ K implies that r m ∈ K for r ∈ R and m ∈ M where α, β are positive integers. This paper is devoted to study the closed submodules. A number of results concerning (α, β)-closed submodules are given.</t></is></c><c r="C71" t="inlineStr"><is><t>closed submodule, semiprime submodule, prime</t></is></c><c r="D71" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E71" t="n"><v>205</v></c><c r="F71" t="n"><v>207</v></c></row><row r="72"><c r="A72" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A way to construction strong d-algebras</t></is></c><c r="B72" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A d-algebra was introduced by Neggers and Kim in 1999 as a generalization of a BCK-algebra. We consider constructive function triples on the real numbers, and construct many strong d-algebras. We obtain some conditions for a d-algebra on the real numbers to be strong.</t></is></c><c r="C72" t="inlineStr"><is><t>BCK-algebra, (strong) d-algebra, constructive functions</t></is></c><c r="D72" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E72" t="n"><v>208</v></c><c r="F72" t="n"><v>212</v></c></row><row r="73"><c r="A73" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(Rees) Locally Noetherian and Artinian S-acts over monoids</t></is></c><c r="B73" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In [4], (Rees) artinian S-acts are introduced as the acts that satisfy the descending chain condition on their (Rees) congruences, and (Rees) noetherian as those acts whose (Rees) congruences are finitely generated. In this paper, we introduce the classes of right S-acts called (Rees) locally artinian (noetherian) as the acts that all their finitely generated subacts are (Rees) artinian (noetherian). We give some general properties of (Rees) locally artinian (noetherian) and discuss the behaviour of such acts under Rees short exact sequence and coproduct. Also, some characterizations of monoids over which all S-acts are (Rees) locally artinian (noetherian) are obtained.</t></is></c><c r="C73" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Locally Noetherian, Locally Artinian, S-acts, Monoids</t></is></c><c r="D73" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E73" t="n"><v>213</v></c><c r="F73" t="n"><v>217</v></c></row><row r="74"><c r="A74" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Algebra and Uncertainty Business; A missing ring in</t></is></c><c r="B74" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Algebra is the branch of mathematics that deals with the manipulation of equations and variables. Algebra is used in business to solve problems involving equations. For example, businesses use algebra to calculate the break-even point, which is the point at which revenue equals expenses. Also, Algebra is widely used in business and everyday life. For example, it can help estimate the lifetime value of a customer or how much that customer will spend. also, algebraic operations can be used to predict sales, determine pricing options, identify patterns in customer behavior, develop a savings plan and more this paper aims to have a brief glance to the implication of Algebra in cutting edge managerial issues .</t></is></c><c r="C74" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Algebra, productivity, business Management</t></is></c><c r="D74" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E74" t="n"><v>218</v></c><c r="F74" t="n"><v>221</v></c></row><row r="75"><c r="A75" t="inlineStr"><is><t>some properties of L-Hutton uniform spaces ,L-fuzzy</t></is></c><c r="B75" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Fuzzy topology is a type of topology defined on a lattice. The study of uniformity structures on L-valued spaces has been extensively explored in the literature, with quasi-uniformity emerging as a useful tool for investigating topology, proximity, closure, and interior operators. This paper introduces the concept of L-Hutton uniform spaces and explores their properties. We investigate the relationship betweenL-fuzzy topological spaces and L-Hutton uniform spaces, demonstrating that every [0, 1]-fuzzy topological space is Hutton[0, 1]-quasi-uniformizable. Our findings contribute to the development of new tools for studying topology and related concepts in fuzzy mathematics.</t></is></c><c r="C75" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Lfuzzy topological spaces, uniformity structure, L-</t></is></c><c r="D75" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E75" t="n"><v>222</v></c><c r="F75" t="n"><v>227</v></c></row><row r="76"><c r="A76" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Noether Symmetries and corresponding conservation laws</t></is></c><c r="B76" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Since Emmy Noether proved that there is a one-to-one correspondence between symmetry groups and conservation laws. A new range of symmetries called Neother symmetries were formed. In this article, we are trying to obtain the Noether symmetries of the mKdV equation and show by finding the conservation law by direct method that corresponding to each of the mentioned symmetries, a similar survival law is obtained.</t></is></c><c r="C76" t="inlineStr"><is><t>mKdV equation, Neother symmetries, direct method</t></is></c><c r="D76" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E76" t="n"><v>228</v></c><c r="F76" t="n"><v>232</v></c></row><row r="77"><c r="A77" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Conditions under which the power series ring</t></is></c><c r="B77" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A right gr-ring is a class of reversible rings that have been the subject of many researches so far. In this paper, we demonstrate if R[[x]] is a right gr-ring, then R is also a right gr-ring. Also, we try to obtain conditions under which R[[x]] is a right gr-ring. For this purpose, we prove that if R is a von Neumann right gr-ring, then R[[x]] is a symmetric ring. Finally, it is asserted that if the power series ring R[[x]] of a von Neumann right gr-ring R is a left self injective ring, then R[[x]] is a right gr-ring.</t></is></c><c r="C77" t="inlineStr"><is><t>right gr-ring, power series, symmetric ring, self injective</t></is></c><c r="D77" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E77" t="n"><v>233</v></c><c r="F77" t="n"><v>239</v></c></row><row r="78"><c r="A78" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Some graph theoretical properties of character graph of</t></is></c><c r="B78" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let H be a finite group. The set of prime numbers that divide a degree of the irreducible characters of H is denoted by ρ(H). The character graph ∆(H) has been defined as a graph with the set of vertices ρ(H), and there exists an edge {r, s} in ∆(H) if there is an irreducible character of H such that its degree is divisible by rs. Here, we present several properties of ∆(H) from a graph theoretical perspective, including the number of distinct eigenvalues and cut vertices. These properties provide insight into the shape of ∆(H). Additionally, we provide bounds on the size and the matching number of ∆(H).</t></is></c><c r="C78" t="inlineStr"><is><t>character graphs, eigenvalue, matching number, cut</t></is></c><c r="D78" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E78" t="n"><v>240</v></c><c r="F78" t="n"><v>244</v></c></row><row r="79"><c r="A79" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Investigating the detection of fraud in car accidents using</t></is></c><c r="B79" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Fraud is a common problem in the insurance industry that causes heavy losses both in terms of material benefits and public trust. One of the most common violations is organized and opportunistic fraud in car insurance. Intentional accidents, especially in the majority of groups, people getting hurt by vehicles or staging are among the common frauds in this field. The purpose of this paper is to identify large fraud clusters or in other words, professional or organized frauds. In this research, the researchers first introduce a network called the accident network using graph theory. Then suspicious clusters in this network are identified by an algorithm based on graph theory. Then the authors use random processes to label each car’s suspicion of fraud.</t></is></c><c r="C79" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Insurance Fraud, Network analysis, Algorithm, Graph</t></is></c><c r="D79" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E79" t="n"><v>245</v></c><c r="F79" t="n"><v>250</v></c></row><row r="80"><c r="A80" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Relations between the domination numbers of zero divisor</t></is></c><c r="B80" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let R be a commutative ring with non zero identity and I be an ideal of R. In this talk we study some relations between domination numbers of zero divisor graph Γ(R), The ideal-based zero divisor graph Γ (R) and the annihilating ideal graph of R, AG(R). I</t></is></c><c r="C80" t="inlineStr"><is><t>domination number, zero divisor graph, ideal-based zero</t></is></c><c r="D80" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E80" t="n"><v>251</v></c><c r="F80" t="n"><v>253</v></c></row><row r="81"><c r="A81" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A Review on using modularity measure in detecting</t></is></c><c r="B81" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Modularity is an important part of community detection algorithms. This measure provides a formula for calculating the quality of dividing nodes into different communities, which has become the most widely used quantitative measure for quality measurement community detection algorithms due to its simplicity and effectiveness. In this paper, different variations of modularity for different types of networks and algorithms based on modularity optimization are will be study in detection communities in network.</t></is></c><c r="C81" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Social network, community detection, algorithm</t></is></c><c r="D81" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E81" t="n"><v>254</v></c><c r="F81" t="n"><v>259</v></c></row><row r="82"><c r="A82" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Entropy and the Number of Cliques in a Graph</t></is></c><c r="B82" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let c be the number of cliques with k vertices in a graph. k Using the concept of entropy from information theory, we prove that the √ (cid:8) (cid:9)∞ sequence k c is a monotonically decreasing sequence. In particular, k k=1 k in a graph with m edges c is at most m . 2 k</t></is></c><c r="C82" t="inlineStr"><is><t>clique, entropy</t></is></c><c r="D82" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E82" t="n"><v>260</v></c><c r="F82" t="n"><v>262</v></c></row><row r="83"><c r="A83" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Some results on Sombor energy of graphs</t></is></c><c r="B83" t="inlineStr"><is><t>For a simple graph G the Sombor index of G is defined as (cid:112) (cid:80) 2 2 SO(G) = d + d , where d is the vertex degree of v. The v u v uv∈E(G) Sombor energy, is the energy of Sombor matrix of G. In this paper we find some new bounds for Sombor energy. We show that our results improve some previous bounds.</t></is></c><c r="C83" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Sombor index; Sombor energy</t></is></c><c r="D83" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E83" t="n"><v>263</v></c><c r="F83" t="n"><v>266</v></c></row><row r="84"><c r="A84" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The number of automorphisms with a fixed number of fixed</t></is></c><c r="B84" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Suppose that G is a finite group and Aut(G) is the group of its automorphisms. For each α ∈ Aut(G), the set of fixed points of α is denoted by F (α) and is defined as F (α) = {g ∈ G | α(g) = g}. Let d be a divisor of |G|. We define the set S as S = {α ∈ Aut(G) | |F (α)| = d} and the theta d d function as θ(d) = |S |. Calculation of the values of theta function is a d computational problem that is done for some finite groups, such as dihedral group D , where q is a prime number. In this paper, we will calculate the 2q values of the theta function for the dihedral group D , where p and q are 2pq two prime numbers.</t></is></c><c r="C84" t="inlineStr"><is><t>fixed point, automorphism, θ-function, dihedral group</t></is></c><c r="D84" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E84" t="n"><v>267</v></c><c r="F84" t="n"><v>271</v></c></row><row r="85"><c r="A85" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Enhanced power graph of a finite group</t></is></c><c r="B85" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The enhanced power graph P (G) of a group G is a graph with e vertex set G, where two vertices u and v are adjacent if and only if &lt; u, v &gt; is cyclic. In this paper, we raise and study the following question: For which natural numbers n every two groups of order n with isomorphic enhanced power graphs are isomorphic?</t></is></c><c r="C85" t="inlineStr"><is><t>enhanced power graph, power graph, isomorphism</t></is></c><c r="D85" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E85" t="n"><v>272</v></c><c r="F85" t="n"><v>275</v></c></row><row r="86"><c r="A86" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Roman domination number in the unitary Cayley graphs</t></is></c><c r="B86" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, We investigate the Roman domination number of some unitary Cayley graph corresponding to a finite ring with nonzero identity R, and find some classes of Roman unitary Cayley graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C86" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Unitary Cayley graph, Domination number, Roman</t></is></c><c r="D86" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E86" t="n"><v>276</v></c><c r="F86" t="n"><v>278</v></c></row><row r="87"><c r="A87" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Dynamic Monopolies of Simple Graphs</t></is></c><c r="B87" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We consider the following simultaneous polling game played on a simple connected graph with vertices colored black or white. During each round of the game, each vertex v is recolored according to the following rule: If at round t more than half of the elements of N[v] (closed neighborhood of v) are colored with c, then at round t+1 the vertex v will be c and if exactly half of the elements of N[v] colored white and other half colored black, v is colored by white. A set of vertices S is said to be a dynamic monopoly, abbreviated dynamo, if starting the game with the vertices of S colored white, the system eventually reaches an all-white global state. We denote the smallest size of any dynamic monopoly of G by dyn(G). In this talk, we study dyn(G) for some special classes of graphs. In particular, we study the case that G is a link of two other graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C87" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Dynamic monopolies, Repetitive Polling Game, majority</t></is></c><c r="D87" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E87" t="n"><v>279</v></c><c r="F87" t="n"><v>284</v></c></row><row r="88"><c r="A88" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Type-II APM-LDPC Codes with Girth 6</t></is></c><c r="B88" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, for the first time, Type-II APM-LDPC codes are presented as a class of APM-LDPC codes whose parity-check matrices (PCMs) include blocks comprising by combining two non-overlapping APMs. Then, some conditions are provided to give Type-II APM-LDPC codes with girth at least 6 and a table containing of the 4-cycle free constructed codes with will be given.</t></is></c><c r="C88" t="inlineStr"><is><t>LDPC codes, girth, affine permutation matrix</t></is></c><c r="D88" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E88" t="n"><v>285</v></c><c r="F88" t="n"><v>290</v></c></row><row r="89"><c r="A89" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the Norms of Circulant Matrices Connected Particular</t></is></c><c r="B89" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Some generalizations of Pell sequence and Pell-Lucas sequence are considered in this paper. We obtain the eigenvalues and determinants of particular circulant matrices involving these sequences. Finally, we obtain some upper and lower bounds for the spectral norms of these circulant matrices.</t></is></c><c r="C89" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(k, h)-Pell-Lucas sequence, Eigenvalue, Determinant</t></is></c><c r="D89" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E89" t="n"><v>291</v></c><c r="F89" t="n"><v>296</v></c></row><row r="90"><c r="A90" t="inlineStr"><is><t>2-restricted optimal pebbling number of a graph</t></is></c><c r="B90" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The weight of a configuration f on a simple graph G which is (cid:80) N a function f : V → ∪ {0} is w(f ) = f (u). A pebbling step from u∈V a vertex u to one of its neighbors v reduces f (u) by two and increases f (v) by one. A pebbling configuration f is a t-restricted pebbling configuration (abbreviated tRPC) if f (v) ≤ t for all v ∈ V . The t-restricted optimal ∗ pebbling number π (G) is the minimum weight of a solvable tRPC on G. t In this paper, we characterize graphs having 2-restricted optimal pebbling ∗ number 5 and improve the upper bound of π for trees. 2</t></is></c><c r="C90" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Domination, roman domination, t-restricted pebbling</t></is></c><c r="D90" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E90" t="n"><v>297</v></c><c r="F90" t="n"><v>300</v></c></row><row r="91"><c r="A91" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Well-independent dominated graphs</t></is></c><c r="B91" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A dominating set in a graph G = (V, E) is a set S such that every vertex of G is either in S or adjacent to a vertex in S. The minimum cardinality of a dominating set in G is called the domination number of G denoted by γ(G), and the maximum cardinality of a minimal dominating set in G is called the upper domination number of G denoted by Γ(G). The difference between these two parameters is called the domination gap of G and denote it by μ (G) = Γ(G) − γ(G). A graph G with μ (G) = 0 is called d d a well-dominated graph. Motivated by this, we introduce well-independent dominated graphs. A graph G with μ (G) = Γ (G) − γ (G) = 0 is called id i i a well-independent dominated graph, where γ (G) and Γ (G) are indepen- i i dent domination number and upper independent domination number of G, respectively. We obtain some results on well-independent dominated graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C91" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Domination, independent domination, well independent</t></is></c><c r="D91" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E91" t="n"><v>301</v></c><c r="F91" t="n"><v>304</v></c></row><row r="92"><c r="A92" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On neighbourhood Laplacian matrix of graphs</t></is></c><c r="B92" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a graph with the vertex set V (G) = {v , . . . , v }. Due 1 n to [C. Godsil and G. Royele, Algebraic Graph Theory, Springer, New York (2001)], a symmetric matrix L of order n is called a generalized Laplacian of G if L &lt; 0 when v and v are adjacent vertices of G and L = 0 when v v i i v v i j i j v and v are distinct and not adjacent. i j The 2-degree of the vertex v ∈ V (G), denoted by S (v ), is defined to i i G (cid:80) be the sum of degrees of neighbours of v , i.e., S (v ) = d (x). Let i i ∼ G G x v i A(G) be the adjacency matrix of a graph G. The neighbourhood Laplacian matrix of G, which is defined as L (G) = diag(S (v ), · · · , S (v )) − A(G), N G 1 G n ′ ′ ′ is a generalized Laplacian of G. Let μ ≥ μ ≥ . . . ≥ μ be the eigenvalues 1 2 n of L (G). N In this paper, we first show that L (G) is positive semi-definite. N ′ ∆ ≤ μ ≤ ∆ + ∆, N 1 N where ∆ = max{S (x) | x ∈ V (G)} and ∆ = max{d (x) | x ∈ V (G)}. N G G ′ Finally, we show that if G is a connected graph of order n, then μ is a n simple eigenvalue of L (G) and the corresponding eigenvector can be taken N to have all its entries positive.</t></is></c><c r="C92" t="inlineStr"><is><t>generalized Laplacian, 2-degree, neighbourhood Zagreb</t></is></c><c r="D92" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E92" t="n"><v>305</v></c><c r="F92" t="n"><v>309</v></c></row><row r="93"><c r="A93" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Particular Number Sequences, Some Properties and</t></is></c><c r="B93" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Some generalizations of Pell sequence and Pell-Lucas sequence are considered in this paper. We obtain generating functions, some identities and formulas for the sums of a finite number of terms and consecutive terms, sums of squares of consecutive terms and alternating sums of consecutive terms of these sequences.</t></is></c><c r="C93" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(k, h)-Pell-Lucas sequence, Consecutive term</t></is></c><c r="D93" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E93" t="n"><v>310</v></c><c r="F93" t="n"><v>315</v></c></row><row r="94"><c r="A94" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The improved bounds for the Seidel and Seidel Laplacian</t></is></c><c r="B94" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let A and S be the adjacency and Seidel matrises of G. The Seidel energy of G, denoted by E (G), is defined as the sum of the absolute s values of the Seidel eigenvalues of G, that is E (G) = |λ | + · · · + |λ |. In this s 1 n work, spectral features of the Seidel and Seidel Laplacian matrix of graphs are determined. By using these features and other techniques, some bounds are obtained for the Seidel and Seidel Laplacian energy of graphs. Further, improved bounds for the Seidel and Seidel Laplacian energy.</t></is></c><c r="C94" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Seidel matrix, Seidel Laplacian matrix, Eigenvalue</t></is></c><c r="D94" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E94" t="n"><v>316</v></c><c r="F94" t="n"><v>318</v></c></row><row r="95"><c r="A95" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Bounds for a heterogeneity measure of complex networks</t></is></c><c r="B95" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Today, complex networks play an important role in various sci- ences. The heterogeneity measure is a index that can quantify the diversity of connections between vertices or nodes in networks even with different topolo- gies. the diversity in node degrees and the diversity in the structure of the network are the two topics that are investigated by the heterogeneity mea- 1 1 (cid:80) 2 sure. the measure, proposed by Estrada is ρ = ( √ − ) , (cid:112) (v ,v )∈E(G) i j k k i j where v ∈ V (G), the degree of v , written by k , is the number of edges in- i i i cident with v . In this paper, we will compute upper and lower bound of ρ i and also for which graph ρ gives second smallest and largest value.</t></is></c><c r="C95" t="inlineStr"><is><t>complex networks, heterogeneity measure, upper and</t></is></c><c r="D95" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E95" t="n"><v>319</v></c><c r="F95" t="n"><v>323</v></c></row><row r="96"><c r="A96" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Perfect Star Packing and Pseudo-Matching in Fullerene</t></is></c><c r="B96" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Fullerenes are 3-connected, 3-regular planar graphs with only pentagonal and hexagonal faces. A perfect star packing in a fullerene graph G is a spanning subgraph of G whose each component of G is isomorphic to the star graph K and a perfect pseudo matching of G is a spanning 1,3 subgraph of G such that each component of its is either K or K . In this 2 1,3 presentation, we study and compute the number of perfect star packings and pseudo-matching in some classes of fullerene graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C96" t="inlineStr"><is><t>perfect star packing, perfect pseudo-matching, fullerene</t></is></c><c r="D96" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E96" t="n"><v>324</v></c><c r="F96" t="n"><v>328</v></c></row><row r="97"><c r="A97" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Commuting Conjugacy Class Graph of The Generalized</t></is></c><c r="B97" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Suppose G is a finite non-abelian group. The commuting conjugacy class graph of G is denoted by Γ(G). This is a simple graph with the non-central conjugacy classes of G as its vertex set. Two distinct vertices C and D of this graph are assumed to be adjacent if and only if cd = dc, for some c ∈ C and d ∈ D. In this paper, the structure of the commuting conjugacy class graph of the generalized dicyclic group are completely determined.</t></is></c><c r="C97" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Commuting conjugacy class graph, The generalized</t></is></c><c r="D97" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E97" t="n"><v>332</v></c><c r="F97" t="n"><v>333</v></c></row><row r="98"><c r="A98" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Sharp bounds for Seidel Estrada index of a graph</t></is></c><c r="B98" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a simple graph of order n. The Seidel Estrada index of (cid:80) n μ G is SEE(G) = e , where μ , . . . , μ are the eigenvalues of the Seidel i 1 n i=1 matrix of G. In this paper we obtain some bounds for the Seidel Estrada index of graphs in terms of the number of vertices. As a consequence we confirm some conjectures.</t></is></c><c r="C98" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Seidel matrix; Seidel Estrada index</t></is></c><c r="D98" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E98" t="n"><v>334</v></c><c r="F98" t="n"><v>337</v></c></row><row r="99"><c r="A99" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A Study of Prof. Alireza Ashrafi’s Research in Graph</t></is></c><c r="B99" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Prof. Alireza Ashrafi was a mathematician who works in the fields of mathematical chemistry, computational group theory, chemical graph theory, finite groups and mathematical physics1. He was a professor at the Department of Pure Mathematics, Faculty of Mathematical Sciences, University of Kashan, Kashan, Iran. He had published more than 300 papers in international journals and has a high citation record. He has also organized and participated in many conferences and workshops on algebraic combinatorics and graph theory. He has studied the symmetry and properties of various types of carbon nanotubes and nanotori using graph theory. Prof. Alireza Ashrafi had done extensive research in graph theory, especially in the areas of chemical graph theory and algebraic combinatorics. He has applied graph theory to study the symmetry, topological indices, polynomials and properties of various types of carbon nanostructures, such as fullerenes, nanotubes, nanotori and nanocones. He has also used computational group theory to investigate the permutation-inversion groups and the automorphism groups of different classes of graphs. In this paper, we review Prof. Alireza Ashrafi’s research in graph theory.</t></is></c><c r="C99" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Prof. Alireza Ashrafi, Metric graph theory, Topological</t></is></c><c r="D99" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E99" t="n"><v>338</v></c><c r="F99" t="n"><v>341</v></c></row><row r="100"><c r="A100" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The dual cozero-divsor graph of Z</t></is></c><c r="B100" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let R be a commutative ring with non-zero identity. The dual ′ of cozero-divisor graph of R, denoted byΓ (R), is a graph with vertices ∗ W (R), and two distinct elements a and b are adjacent if and only if a ∈ bR or b ∈ aR. In this paper we characterize the dual graph of Z . n</t></is></c><c r="C100" t="inlineStr"><is><t>cozero-divisor graph, dual of cozero-divisor graph</t></is></c><c r="D100" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E100" t="n"><v>342</v></c><c r="F100" t="n"><v>345</v></c></row><row r="101"><c r="A101" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Decision-Making Based on Hypergraphs</t></is></c><c r="B101" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper considers the notation of T.B.T (total binary truth table) and applies a novel concept of hypergraphable Boolean functions and Boolean functionable hypergraphs with respect to any given T.B.T to introduce the binary decision hypertrees. The major contribution of this work is to introduce the novel and simple method to the design of reduced ordered binary decision diagrams via the hypergraph(tree)s for the first time in this paper.</t></is></c><c r="C101" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Binary decision (hyper) diagram, Binary decision (hyper) tree</t></is></c><c r="D101" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E101" t="n"><v>346</v></c><c r="F101" t="n"><v>350</v></c></row><row r="102"><c r="A102" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Intermediate Axiom On Algebraic Structure</t></is></c><c r="B102" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this article, we introduce the concept of superhyperalgebra and show that superhyperalgebra is a useful generalization of algebra and expresses the development of the mainproperties of logic algebra. Our method is to extend G-algebras to (m, n)-superhyper G-algebras using the concept of power set of a set. More precisely, we define the 0-commutative (m, n)-superhyper G-subalgebra and present several results from the study of some properties of (m, n)-superhyper G-algebra.</t></is></c><c r="C102" t="inlineStr"><is><t>(m, n)-super hyper operation, (m, n)-super hyper</t></is></c><c r="D102" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E102" t="n"><v>351</v></c><c r="F102" t="n"><v>355</v></c></row><row r="103"><c r="A103" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Vertex degrees and cut vertices in compact graphs</t></is></c><c r="B103" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A simple graph G with no isolated vertices is called a compact graph if for each pair x, y of non-adjacent vertices of G, there is a vertex z with N(x) ∪ N(y) ⊆ N(z), where N(v) is the neighborhood of v, for every vertex v of G. In this paper, the vertex degrees of compact graphs are studied. Also, the structure of regular compact graphs is determined. Among other results, we find conditions under which adding or removing vertices from compact graph results in a compact graph. Some results about cut vertices in compact graphs are proved, too.</t></is></c><c r="C103" t="inlineStr"><is><t>compact graph, vertex degree, neighborhood, cut vertex</t></is></c><c r="D103" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E103" t="n"><v>356</v></c><c r="F103" t="n"><v>360</v></c></row><row r="104"><c r="A104" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Bounds for graph energy in terms of domination number</t></is></c><c r="B104" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a graph. In this work, we obtain a lower bounds for the energy of graphs and give some relations between the energy, domination number and total domination number of G.</t></is></c><c r="C104" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Energy of graph, domination number, perfect matching</t></is></c><c r="D104" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E104" t="n"><v>361</v></c><c r="F104" t="n"><v>364</v></c></row><row r="105"><c r="A105" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A Note on Random Graphs</t></is></c><c r="B105" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The study of random graphs emerged as a distinct field with the influential paper by Erd ̈os and R ́enyi, and it is widely regarded as one of the most important areas within graph theory. Different models of random graphs exist, each characterized by its unique probability distribution for generating graphs. One approach involves starting with individual vertices and randomly adding edges between them. Various random graph models generate distinct probability distributions for the resulting graphs. One of the frequently studied models is denoted as G(n, p), encompassing all labeled graphs with n vertices. In this model, each possible edge appears ⩽ ⩽ independently with a probability of 0 p 1. Another natural model of random graphs is denoted as G(n, m), which represents the probability space of all labeled graphs with n vertices and exactly m edges.</t></is></c><c r="C105" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Random graphs, Expectation, Zagreb indices</t></is></c><c r="D105" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E105" t="n"><v>365</v></c><c r="F105" t="n"><v>368</v></c></row><row r="106"><c r="A106" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the soft coloring of soft graphs</t></is></c><c r="B106" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A proper coloring of a graph is an assignment of colors to the vertices (edges) of the graph so that no two adjacent vertices (edges) have the same color. In this paper, we introduce and investigate the generalizations of the vertex coloring using the concept of soft sets. Soft set theory is a generalization of fuzzy set theory, that was proposed by Molodtsov in 1999 to deal with uncertainty in a parametric manner. By combining the concepts of graphs and soft sets, the notion of soft graph was introduced. We show that the definition of soft coloring in a soft graph unifies the concepts of vertex coloring, edge coloring and coloring of hypergraphs.</t></is></c><c r="C106" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Soft sets, soft graphs, soft coloring of soft graphs, total</t></is></c><c r="D106" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E106" t="n"><v>369</v></c><c r="F106" t="n"><v>375</v></c></row><row r="107"><c r="A107" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Legendre multiwavelet basis for solving boundary value</t></is></c><c r="B107" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we introduce a Galerkin-wavelet method using Legendre multiwavelet basis for solving boundary value problems with Dirichlet condition and describe its advantages by implementing the method on a numerical example.</t></is></c><c r="C107" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Legendre multiwavelet, Galerkin method, condition</t></is></c><c r="D107" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E107" t="n"><v>376</v></c><c r="F107" t="n"><v>381</v></c></row><row r="108"><c r="A108" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Numerical solution of fractional Lane-Emden equation using</t></is></c><c r="B108" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The Lane-Emden equation models several phenomena in mathematical physics, mathematical chemistry and astrophysics. Approximate solutions for a class of fractional Lane-Emden type equations is achieved using an efficient spectral Petro-Galerkin method. Basis functions are generalized Jacobi polynomials in such a way that the boundary conditions are satisfied. An error bound for the suggested scheme is also obtained. Numerical results for different values of input parameters, show the high accuracy and low CPU time of proposed scheme.</t></is></c><c r="C108" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Generalized Jacobi polynomials, Lan-Emden equation</t></is></c><c r="D108" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E108" t="n"><v>382</v></c><c r="F108" t="n"><v>387</v></c></row><row r="109"><c r="A109" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The directional g-differentiability of fuzzy multi-dimensional</t></is></c><c r="B109" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper the concepts of directional g-differentiability is framed and the relationship of which will the aforementioned concept is also explored. Finally, to illustrate the ability and reliability of the aforementioned concepts we have solved an example.</t></is></c><c r="C109" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Fuzzy multi-dimensional mappings; g-(linear continuous)</t></is></c><c r="D109" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E109" t="n"><v>388</v></c><c r="F109" t="n"><v>392</v></c></row><row r="110"><c r="A110" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Dickson polynomials neural networks for dynamical system</t></is></c><c r="B110" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Polynomials neural networks are important classes of artificial neural networks. Dickson polynomials have been defined on finite fields. Based on these algebraic polynomials, this work proposes a new neural net- work, and utilizes it for the identification of nonlinear dynamic systems. The efficiency of this model is shown through the simulation results of a bench- mark nonlinear dynamic system.</t></is></c><c r="C110" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Dickson polynomials, neural networks, system</t></is></c><c r="D110" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E110" t="n"><v>393</v></c><c r="F110" t="n"><v>398</v></c></row><row r="111"><c r="A111" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Uncertainty from the point of view of information theory</t></is></c><c r="B111" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this review paper, we talk about the criteria of information theory and fuzzy theory that emphasize uncertainty. Measurements resulting from the combination of these two branches are also called fuzzy information measurements.</t></is></c><c r="C111" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Information measure, uncertainty, entropy, fuzzy set</t></is></c><c r="D111" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E111" t="n"><v>399</v></c><c r="F111" t="n"><v>404</v></c></row><row r="112"><c r="A112" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Regression models with stationary autocorrelated errors</t></is></c><c r="B112" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In multiple regression model, it usually assumed that the error terms are independent. However, ignoring the autocorrelation or dependency between the errors is risky with respect to validity because of the damage that is done to the model. Autocorrelated error terms require modification of the usual methods of the estimation. One parametric approach that may be used to avoid this problem is to consider an ARMA model for the errors of the model then regressing a transformed model.</t></is></c><c r="C112" t="inlineStr"><is><t>linear regression, correlated covariance structure, time</t></is></c><c r="D112" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E112" t="n"><v>405</v></c><c r="F112" t="n"><v>409</v></c></row><row r="113"><c r="A113" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Classic stochastic models for describing network data</t></is></c><c r="B113" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Random graph as a multidisciplinary topic uses probabilistic ideas to model and understand the real-world networks, such as social networks, biological networks, the Internet, and so on. These models play and central role to describe the structure and to quantify and explain the growing complexity and connectivity of the world around us. The study of random graphs has found applications in various disciplines, including computer science, mathematics, physics, biology, and sociology. By studying and analyzing the properties of random graph models, researchers can gain insights into the underlying mechanisms and dynamics of complex networks. The aim of this paper, is to review some simple random graph models. These models have been widely used to analyze and simulate real-world networks, and they provide insights into the emergence and evolution of network structures.</t></is></c><c r="C113" t="inlineStr"><is><t>random graph models, network structure</t></is></c><c r="D113" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E113" t="n"><v>410</v></c><c r="F113" t="n"><v>415</v></c></row><row r="114"><c r="A114" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Linear mixed model based on the canonical fundamental</t></is></c><c r="B114" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The purpose of this paper is to extend original normal linear mixed model (N-LMM) model for handling missing and heavy tails data. In this model, the random effects have the canonical fundamental skew normal (CFUSN) distribution and errors arise the multivariate normal distribution. An Expectation conditional maximization (ECM) algorithm is developed for parameters estimation based on missing information.The relevant utility of our methodology is exemplified through the analysis of real data sets.</t></is></c><c r="C114" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ECM-algorithm, linear mixed models, the canonical</t></is></c><c r="D114" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E114" t="n"><v>416</v></c><c r="F114" t="n"><v>421</v></c></row><row r="115"><c r="A115" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Robust mixtures of skew distributions with incomplete data</t></is></c><c r="B115" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The aim of this paper is to extend finite mixture model for han- dling missing and heavy tails data. In this model, the random variables have the canonical fundamental skew normal (CFUSN) distribution.. An Expecta- tion conditional maximization (ECM) algorithm is developed for parameters estimation based on missing information. The relevant utility of our method- ology is exemplified through the analysis of real data sets.</t></is></c><c r="C115" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Finite mixture, canonical fundamental skew normal</t></is></c><c r="D115" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E115" t="n"><v>422</v></c><c r="F115" t="n"><v>427</v></c></row><row r="116"><c r="A116" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Graphical presentation of ordered variables in contingency</t></is></c><c r="B116" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Since 1960’s, the analysis of ordered data set in contingency tables has been more attended. Specially, in medical sciences these data have very important role. Our goal is to graphically display the ordered data in contingency tables using easy way.</t></is></c><c r="C116" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ordered random variables, test of fit, contingency tables</t></is></c><c r="D116" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E116" t="n"><v>428</v></c><c r="F116" t="n"><v>433</v></c></row><row r="117"><c r="A117" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A computational method for cost minimization of vibrating</t></is></c><c r="B117" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, a vibrating system whose dynamic is stated by a second order linear differential equation is considered. By introducing some new suitable variables, the vibrating structure will be represented as a Linear Time Invariant (LTI) control system in state space model with a quadratic cost function. The minimum cost will achieve by incorporating a computational method based on Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman (HJB) equation.</t></is></c><c r="C117" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Vibrating system, Cost minimization</t></is></c><c r="D117" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E117" t="n"><v>434</v></c><c r="F117" t="n"><v>438</v></c></row><row r="118"><c r="A118" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Proximal point method for quasi-equilibrium problems in</t></is></c><c r="B118" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In this paper, we propose a proximal point method for finding a solution of quasi-equilibrium problems in Hadamard spaces. In this method a quasi-equilibrium problem is solved by computing a solution of an equilibrium problem at each iteration. We obtain weak convergence of the sequence to a solution of the quasi-equilibrium problems under some mild assumptions.</t></is></c><c r="C118" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Quasi-equilibrium problem, Hadamar space, Strictly</t></is></c><c r="D118" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E118" t="n"><v>439</v></c><c r="F118" t="n"><v>443</v></c></row><row r="119"><c r="A119" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Hopf bifurcation and Turing instability in a cross-diffusion</t></is></c><c r="B119" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This paper is concerned with a cross-diffusion prey-predator system in which the prey species is equipped with the group defense ability under Neumann boundary conditions. We consider the environmental protection of the prey population as a bifurcation parameter. Then, we discuss the Turing instability and the Hopf bifurcation analysis on the proposed model. The positive equilibrium is stable without cross-diffusion under suitable conditions, but it becomes unstable when the cross-diffusion term appears in the system.</t></is></c><c r="C119" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Prey-predator model, Cross-diffusion, Hopf bifurcation</t></is></c><c r="D119" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E119" t="n"><v>444</v></c><c r="F119" t="n"><v>448</v></c></row><row r="120"><c r="A120" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Minimum channel access time in multicast wireless sensor</t></is></c><c r="B120" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In recent years, a technique called network encoding has been provided that have great benefits in computer networks. The network encoding by passing the traditional view of data transfer in a data-storage to data network, network nodes allow network nodes to process processing data. In this technique, the network nodes store packets in their memory to combine and send nodes with other packets. Due to the time constraints on sensor nodes, a management needs to be implemented on the time needed to encode the network in wireless sensor networks. In this research, the network encoding in wireless sensor networks has been investigated with the aim of balancing the use of node time. Then, an optimization problem is modelled. The proposed optimization model can be centrally solved, but to solve the optimization problems, the it needs to collect the information of all nodes in a node and, after solving the problem, provides an optimal solution for the nodes. Thus, solving the model presented in relatively large networks is impractical and almost impossible and not suitable for the wireless sensor networks. As a result, using a conjugate gradient method and a flow segmentation technique, a distributed and repeatable algorithm is presented to solve the problem. In the proposed distributed algorithm, each node decides locally and based on the information of its neighbour nodes. Evaluating the efficiency of the proposed method is done by simulation while the results show that the proposed algorithm reduces the overflow in the sensor nodes and the delay.</t></is></c><c r="C120" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Wireless Sensor Network, WSN, network coding</t></is></c><c r="D120" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E120" t="n"><v>449</v></c><c r="F120" t="n"><v>453</v></c></row><row r="121"><c r="A121" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Consensus-based algorithm for distributed convex</t></is></c><c r="B121" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The distributed convex optimization problem is investigated in this article. A consensus-based algorithm is designed in combination with the gradient descent method. Using the Lyapunov theory, the convergence of this algorithm to the optimal solution is analyzed. In addition to theoretical results, simulation results are presented to state the efficiency of the offered algorithm.</t></is></c><c r="C121" t="inlineStr"><is><t>distributed convex optimization, consensus, gradient</t></is></c><c r="D121" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E121" t="n"><v>454</v></c><c r="F121" t="n"><v>459</v></c></row><row r="122"><c r="A122" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A convex combination of decay step sizes for SGD</t></is></c><c r="B122" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The decay step size is widely recognized as one of the most ef- ficient methods for determining the learning rate in stochastic gradient de- scent (SGD). While there have been several approaches proposed for decay step sizes, this paper focuses on enhancing the efficiency of the cosine step size in practical scenarios. To achieve this, we propose a convex combination 1 of the cosine and step sizes. For this convex combination, we provide √ t 1 an O( ) rate of convergence for smooth non-convex functions without the √ T Polyak-L(cid:32) ojasiewicz condition. In terms of numerical results, we implement SGD on the FashionMNIST, CIFAR10, and CIFAR100 datasets. We demon- strate that the new step size improves the accuracy and loss function of the cosine step size.</t></is></c><c r="C122" t="inlineStr"><is><t>stochastic gradient descent, decay step size, convergence</t></is></c><c r="D122" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E122" t="n"><v>460</v></c><c r="F122" t="n"><v>465</v></c></row><row r="123"><c r="A123" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Watermarking the Official Letters</t></is></c><c r="B123" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Blind watermarking algorithms are designed to embed a watermark into a digital file without requiring the original file for extraction. Here we present a new blind algorithm to embed a watermark into an official letter which is resistant against different attacks such as rotation either in clock wise or anti-clock wise direction and cropping.</t></is></c><c r="C123" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Blind Watermarking, Official Letters, Letter Body</t></is></c><c r="D123" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E123" t="n"><v>466</v></c><c r="F123" t="n"><v>471</v></c></row><row r="124"><c r="A124" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Inverse eigenvalue problem for special symmetric matrices</t></is></c><c r="B124" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The purpose of this research was considering the inverse eigenvalue problem for the bordered diagonal. The necessary and sufficient conditions for existence of a symmetric bordered diagonal matrix from special spectral data have been determined. A new algorithm to make such matrices is derived and a numerical example is given to illustrate the efficiency of the method.</t></is></c><c r="C124" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Inverse eigenvalue problem, Bordered diagonal matrix</t></is></c><c r="D124" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E124" t="n"><v>472</v></c><c r="F124" t="n"><v>478</v></c></row><row r="125"><c r="A125" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On robustness for set-valued optimization problems</t></is></c><c r="B125" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Robust optimization is an important subfield of optimization that deals with uncertainty in the data of optimization problems. Consider the robust set-valued optimization problem min F (x, ξ) subject to x ∈ X, (RSOP ) ⇒ Rk where F : X × U Y is a set-valued map, where U ⊆ is the set of uncertainty. ⇒ we define a set-valued map F : X Y as U (cid:91) F (x) = F (x, ξ). U ξ∈U We consider the following set-valued robust counterpart to (RSOP): min F (x) U subject to x ∈ X. (SOP ) In this paper, we study the existence robust efficient solution for robust set- valued optimization problem with unbounded feasible sets by noncoercivity condition via asymptotic analytic tools.</t></is></c><c r="C125" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Robust set-valued optimization problem, Asymptotic</t></is></c><c r="D125" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E125" t="n"><v>479</v></c><c r="F125" t="n"><v>480</v></c></row><row r="126"><c r="A126" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Noncoercive and Noncontinuous Minimax Problems</t></is></c><c r="B126" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Techniques and principles of Minimax theory play a key role in many areas of research, including game theory, optimization. Arguably the most important result in zero-sum games, the Minimax Theorem was stated by John von Neumann in 1928 which was considered the starting point of game theory. Formally, von Neumann’s minimax theorem states: Rn Rm R Let X ⊂ and Y ⊂ be compact convex sets. If f : X × Y → is a continuous function that is concave-convex, i.e. R (1) f (·, y) : X → is concave for fixed y , and R (2) f (x, ·) : Y → is convex for fixed x. Then max min f (x, y) = min max f (x, y). x∈X y∈Y y∈Y x∈X In this paper, By using asymptotic function, as the main result, we prove Minimax Theorem under weaker assumptions of continuity and convexity, when the feasible set is an unbounded.</t></is></c><c r="C126" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Minimax Theorem, Asymptotic function</t></is></c><c r="D126" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E126" t="n"><v>481</v></c><c r="F126" t="n"><v>482</v></c></row><row r="127"><c r="A127" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the Difference Graph of a finite group</t></is></c><c r="B127" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The power graph of a finite group G is a simple undirected graph with vertex set G and two vertices are adjacent if one is a power of the other. The enhanced power graph of a finite group G is a simple undirected graph whose vertex set is the group G and two vertices a and b are adjacent if there exists c ∈ G such that both a and b are powers of c. The difference graph D(G) of a finite group G, which is the difference of the enhanced power graph and the power graph of G with all isolated vertices removed, has been studied in [2]. In this paper, the difference graphs of groups are explored further. In this connection, we study the difference graphs of finite groups with forbidden subgraphs among other results. We first characterize an arbitrary finite group G such that D(G) is a chordal graph, star graph, dominatable, threshold graph, and split graph. From this, we conclude that the latter four graph classes are equivalent for D(G). By applying these results, we classify the nilpotent groups G such that D(G) belong to the aforementioned five graph classes. This shows that all these graph classes are equivalent for D(G) when G is nilpotent. Then, we characterize the nilpotent groups whose difference graphs are cograph, bipartite, Eulerian, planar, and outerplanar. Finally, we consider the difference graph of non-nilpotent groups and determine the values of n such that the difference graphs of the symmetric group S and alternating group n A are cograph, chordal, split, and threshold. n</t></is></c><c r="C127" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Enhanced power graph, power graph, nilpotent groups</t></is></c><c r="D127" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E127" t="n"><v>483</v></c><c r="F127" t="n"><v>484</v></c></row><row r="128"><c r="A128" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A new computational method based on Vieta-Lucas</t></is></c><c r="B128" t="inlineStr"><is><t>In the present study, a new computational method based on the operational matrix of shifted Vieta-Lucas polynomials has been developed to solve the nonlinear Riccati differential equations of fractional- order. By using collocation points and the fractional derivative operator matrix in the Caputo sense, the existing initial value nonlinear equations are converted into a system of nonlinear algebraic equations and by solving this system, the numerical solutions of the fractional Riccati equations are obtained. The numerical solutions obtained in the given examples have good convergence to the exact solutions, which shows the accuracy and efficiency of this compu- tational technique.</t></is></c><c r="C128" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Shifted Vieta-Lucas polynomials, Caputo derivative</t></is></c><c r="D128" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E128" t="n"><v>485</v></c><c r="F128" t="n"><v>486</v></c></row><row r="129"><c r="A129" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Legendre wavelet operational scheme for solving the model</t></is></c><c r="B129" t="inlineStr"><is><t>This work presents the application of the Legendre wavelets method to the model of pollution for a system of three lakes interconnected by chan- nels. This method is based on Legendre polynomials. Three input mod- els (Periodic, Exponentially and Linear) are solved to show that Legendre wavelets method can provide numerical solutions of pollution model in con- vergent series form. The numerical examples are included to demonstrate the validity and applicability of the technique. The results show the efficiency and accuracy of the present method.</t></is></c><c r="C129" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Shifted Legendre polynomials, Legendre wavelets, Water</t></is></c><c r="D129" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E129" t="n"><v>487</v></c><c r="F129" t="n"><v>488</v></c></row><row r="130"><c r="A130" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Cayley Graphs of Gyrogroups: Characteristic Properties</t></is></c><c r="B130" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The concept of gyrogroups was first introduced by Abraham A. Ungar as an extension of the study of Lorentz groups. In 1988, Ungar presented the parametric expression of Lorentz transformations in terms of acceptable relative velocities and directions. The group structure resulting from the realization of the Lorentz group, together with Einstein’s speed addition law, enabled him to establish a profound structural connection between Thomas’s change of direction and Einstein’s addition law.Ungar extended Thomas’s change of direction and referred to its generalized form as Thomas rotation. He showed that rotations are self-distributive and exhibit group-like properties, which he called the gyrogroup. Gyrogroups represent a particular generalization of groups that do not possess associativity. However, the concept of Cayley graphs for gyrogroups was investigated for the first time in a 2019 paper by Bossaban et al. Some properties of Cayley graphs were discussed, and it was found that some properties of Cayley graphs of gyrogroups resemble those of Cayley graphs of groups, while others do not. This non-establishment is due to the non-associative property of gyrogroups.To address this issue, the concept of left Cayley graphs and right Cayley graphs is proposed. In this research, we aim to investigate these features and provide an algorithm for calculating the number of Cayley graphs of a gyrogroup.</t></is></c><c r="C130" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Gyrogroup, Cayley graph, Algorithm</t></is></c><c r="D130" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E130" t="n"><v>489</v></c><c r="F130" t="n"><v>491</v></c></row><row r="131"><c r="A131" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Characterization of rings with planar, toroidal or projective</t></is></c><c r="B131" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let R be a commutative ring with unity. The prime ideal sum graph PIS(R) of the ring R is the simple undirected graph whose vertex set is the set of all nonzero proper ideals of R and two distinct vertices I and J are adjacent if and only if I + J is a prime ideal of R. In this paper, we classify non-local commutative rings R such that PIS(R) is of crosscap at most two. We prove that there does not exist a finite non-local commutative ring whose prime ideal sum graph is projective planar. Further, we classify non-local commutative rings whose prime ideal sum graph is of genus at most two. Moreover, we classify finite non-local commutative rings for which the prime ideal sum graph is split graph, threshold graph, cograph, cactus graph and unicyclic.</t></is></c><c r="C131" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Non-local ring, genus and crosscap of a graph, graph</t></is></c><c r="D131" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E131" t="n"><v>492</v></c><c r="F131" t="n"><v>493</v></c></row><row r="132"><c r="A132" t="inlineStr"><is><t>A note on the spectrum of a graph</t></is></c><c r="B132" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a (n, m)-graph with the vertex set {v , v , . . . , v } 1 2 n and the edge set E(G). The adjancency matrix of G is an n × n matrix A(G) whose ij-entry is 1 if v is adjacent to v and 0, otherwise. i j Eigenvalues of a graph are the roots of characteristic polynomial of the adjancency matrix of it. In this paper, we obtained spectrum of some special subgraphs of complete graph and then estimated some bounds for energy of some graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C132" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Graph, Eigenvalues, Spectrum</t></is></c><c r="D132" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E132" t="n"><v>494</v></c><c r="F132" t="n"><v>495</v></c></row><row r="133"><c r="A133" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ON SOME P −RESTRICTED AUTOMORPHISM</t></is></c><c r="B133" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a finite group, P be a group property and Aut (G) P be the set of all automorphisms α ∈ Aut(G) such that α(H) = H, for any subset H satisfies the property P . The subgroup AutP (G) of Aut(G) is called the P -restricted automorphism group of G. For a finite abelian group H, Dih(H) denotes the generalized dihedral group of H. In this lecture the group structure of Aut (Dih(H)), when P is the property of being a P subgroup, normal subgroup, non-normal subgroup and conjugacy class of Dih(H) are reported.</t></is></c><c r="C133" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Class preserving automorphism group, central</t></is></c><c r="D133" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E133" t="n"><v>496</v></c><c r="F133" t="n"><v>497</v></c></row><row r="134"><c r="A134" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Modules in which every finitely generated its submodule</t></is></c><c r="B134" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We study an R-module M whenever for every (finitely generated) proper submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. Such modules R are called coretractable (co-finite-retractable, or simply CFR). We also consider CFR condition on the factors module, direct sum and direct summand of CFR modules. An R-module M is said to be co-epi-finite-retractable (simply CEFR) whenever for every finitely generated submodule N of M, the factor module M/N can be embedded in M. We investigate if every CFR module is CEFR, then every module is CEFR. Also, we show that R is a semisimple ring if and only if every module is regular if and only if every CFR module is regular. We investigate module M whenever for every cyclic submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. Such modules are called co-cyclic-retractable (simply R CCR). We have examples of CCR modules which are not CFR. We also consider CCR condition on the factors module, direct sum and direct summand of CCR modules.</t></is></c><c r="C134" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Co-finite-retractable, Co-retractable</t></is></c><c r="D134" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E134" t="n"><v>498</v></c><c r="F134" t="n"><v>499</v></c></row><row r="135"><c r="A135" t="inlineStr"><is><t>ON SOME P -RESTRICTED AUTOMORPHISM GROUPS</t></is></c><c r="B135" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Let G be a finite group, P be a group property and Aut (G) P be the set of all automorphisms α ∈ Aut(G) such that α(H) = H, for any subset H satisfies the property P . The subgroup AutP (G) of Aut(G) is called the P -restricted automorphism group of G. For a finite abelian group H, Dic(H, y) denotes the generalized dicyclic group of H where y is a specific element of A with order 2. In this lecture the group structure of Aut (Dic(H, y)), when P is the property of being a subgroup, normal P subgroup, non-normal subgroup and conjugacy class of Dic(H, y) are reported.</t></is></c><c r="C135" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Class preserving automorphism group, central</t></is></c><c r="D135" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E135" t="n"><v>500</v></c><c r="F135" t="n"><v>501</v></c></row><row r="136"><c r="A136" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Constructing Drosophila melanogaster Gene Association</t></is></c><c r="B136" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Regulation of expression of genes and their products, proteins, controls the activities of the cells. Regulating a small collection of genes allows cells to survive in various conditions and grow. These regulatory relationships between genes usually are modeled by networks with various definitions and illustrated by graphs with different characteristics, e.g., gene regulatory networks and gene association networks. Among them, gene asso- ciation networks provided us with valuable insights into gene regulation and enable us to outline genes associated with arbitrary diseases. Also, in this paper, we present a new method to construct gene association networks, net- works that in their corresponding graphs, nodes represent genes and edges between nodes indicate associations, e.g., co-localization, co-expression, or genetic interactions. The proposed method begins by discovering connections between asso- ciations reported in the literature and attributes or annotation of genes. To be precise, it measures the relative importance of attributes associated with the genes on their relationships or associations. By using the obtained results, it is possible to detect known gene associa- tions and estimate strengths for those that have not been reported previously in the literature from attributes or annotations of genes as well. Besides, it is known that genes in a biological network have few associations with their neighboring genes and are in small modules; therefore, in the next step, we use a neural network to find these modules and to fine tune associations derived in the previous step. We conducted several experiments using biological data to measure the accuracy of our proposed method. Experiments have indicated that it can identify both known and novel associations among genes from their annota- tions with high precision and the derived networks are in good agreement with their biological counterparts.</t></is></c><c r="C136" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Neural Networks, Systems Biology, Modules of Genes</t></is></c><c r="D136" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E136" t="n"><v>502</v></c><c r="F136" t="n"><v>503</v></c></row><row r="137"><c r="A137" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On Co-retractable and CFR modules</t></is></c><c r="B137" t="inlineStr"><is><t>We study an R-module M whenever for every proper submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. Such modules are called R coretractable. Amini and et al. investigate coretractable module, and we also obtain some new results of coretractable module. A ring R is called ′ H-ring whenever for every two nonisomorphic simple R-modules S and S , ′ Hom (E(S),E(S )) = 0. We show that, every module over a left Artinian R left H-ring is coretractable. Also, we show that every module M has finite R length over a commutative ring R is coretractable. Recall that, we said an R-module M is co-finite-retractable (simply CFR) whenever for every finitely generated proper submodule K of M, Hom (M/K, M) ̸= 0. It is R clear, every coretractable module is CFR. We consider conditions which under that conditions CFR module and coretractable module are equivalent. We show that, every CFR module is coretractable if and only if every module is coretractable. Also we proved, if every R-module is coretractable, then R is an H-ring and perfect.</t></is></c><c r="C137" t="inlineStr"><is><t>Co-finite-retractable, Co-retractable</t></is></c><c r="D137" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E137" t="n"><v>504</v></c><c r="F137" t="n"><v>505</v></c></row><row r="138"><c r="A138" t="inlineStr"><is><t>On the lexicographic product graphs</t></is></c><c r="B138" t="inlineStr"><is><t>The lexicographic product of two simple graphs G and H, denoted by G ◦ H, is the graph with V (G ◦ H) = V (G) × V (H), and two distinct vertices (g , h ), (g , h ) are adjacent if and only if either 1 1 2 2 g g ∈ E(G) or g = g and h h ∈ E(H). In this paper we investigate 1 2 1 2 1 2 connectivity and super connectivity of the lexicographic product of graphs.</t></is></c><c r="C138" t="inlineStr"><is><t>lexicographic product, connectivity, super connectivity</t></is></c><c r="D138" t="inlineStr"><is><t>en</t></is></c><c r="E138" t="n"><v>506</v></c><c r="F138" t="n"><v>506</v></c></row></sheetData><pageMargins left="0.75" right="0.75" top="1" bottom="1" header="0.5" footer="0.5" /></worksheet>